翻译：RioLiv & Ash十架 @ 微博
水平有限请多指教 压制请保留译者署名
1917年 我自愿入伍去法国打仗
In 1917, I signed up to fight the huns in France.
战场上 周围的好人一个个地死去
Good men died all around me.
我看到他们没理由地 就这么失去生命
And I saw no reason for it.
我们生存的规则变成了谎言
The rules we lived by were lies.
而且炮制规则的人 却不受其限制
And they didn't apply to those who made them.
我发誓如果自己能活着回去 我再也不会循规蹈矩
I swore if I made it home I would never follow orders again.
离家时 我是一名士兵
I left a soldier.
归来时 我成为一名法外之徒
I came home an outlaw.
在新的人生中 抢劫一场接着一场
I lived one robbery to the next.
白天的时间 昏昏欲睡
A good day was filled by sleep
而美妙的夜晚 我们尽情享受 永不回头
and a good night spent running too hard to look back.
十年如一日的生活 就这样过去
I lived that life for 10 years.
直到它的阴影撵上了我
Until it caught up to me.
一切都从一名“线人”开始
It all started with an inside man.
夜 色 人 生
翻译：RioLiv & Ash十架 @ 微博
水平有限请多指教 压制请保留译者署名
Albert White帮 当晚在玩一场赌注极高的牌戏
The Albert white crewwas playing a high stakes
poker game
我们在帮派内的线人 提前帮我们开了后门
and our inside man left the back door
open for us.
三 二 一--
Three, two, one.
把他妈的钱拿出来
Give us the fucking money.
- 哎呀 你们知道你们抢的是谁的地盘吗
- 快拿钱
- Ah, do you know whose fucking place this is?
- Give it!
你知道你们现在糟蹋的是谁的牌局吗 蠢材
I asked, "do you know whose fucking card game this is",
you fucking dunce?
- 听说过Albert White吗
- 你话太多了 傻逼
- You heard of Albert white?
- Keep talking, bimbo.
小姐 过这边来
Miss, come here. Come here!
你们抢钱之前 想喝点什么吗
Do you want a drink to go with your robbery?
不用了 只要钱 把钱放进这个袋子里
No. Just the money. Put it in the bag.
来吧 放进去 就放在这里面 不急
Let's go. In the bag.
Right here. Nice and easy.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫Emma Gould
Emma Gould.
你呢
What's yours?
- 你要把袜子塞到我的嘴里吗
- 是的
- You're gonna put a sock in my mouth?
- That's right.
袜子 塞到我嘴里吗
A sock? In my mouth?
这只袜子从没穿过 我不会骗你的
Never been used before,
and I wouldn't lie to you.
骗子都这么说
That's what all the liars say.
快点 把嘴张开
Quick, open up.
看着点他
Watch this guy.
嘿 把你该死的手放在桌子上
Hey, put your fucking hands on the table.
好极了
Great.
好了 我们走吧
All right, boys. Let's go.
你胆子可真大
You've got some balls.
慢点开 别一副做贼心虚的样子
Just slow down and stop driving
like we did something.
放松点
Relax.
撑过还挺好的 收获不小
We made out pretty good. It was a nice hit.
对 都是因为我厉害
Yeah, it's all mine.
你就是干这个的呗
Yeah. It's a living.
- 去你的吧 死爱尔兰佬
- 别闹 好好开车
- Yeah, you fucking Mick. Get the fuck out of here.
- Drive the car.
午安
Good afternoon.
我是Albert White
I'm Albert white.
你一定就是Joe了
You must be Joe.
对 Joe Coughlin
Coughlin.
不错 终于把名字和脸对起来了
Good to put a face to the name.
这是Brandon Loomis 我的一个朋友
This is Brennan loomis, friend of mine.
你好吗
How are you?
你跟两个蠢家伙 搞些几块几十块钱的小偷小摸
You're too smart for the stuff
you've been pulling.
真有些大材小用
Nickel and diming with two dumb guineas.
他们虽然是你的朋友 但也不过是两个意大利蠢货
They're your friends, but they're stupid
and they're wops.
他们连四十岁都活不过
And they won't live to see 40.
给你点时间考虑
Take your time.
记住 你不可能一个人成事的
But you can't work on your own.
在这里绝对不可能
Not in this town.
Albert正在城市里召集人马
Albert was rounding up the troops.
这里正在进行一场悄无声息的私酒战争
There was a war going on over rum.
Dermot 我们得聊聊
Dermot, go and have a word.
参战双方是Albert White的爱尔兰帮
Brennan 给我盯住他
Albert White ran the Irish mob.
Brennan, keep an eye on him.
好的
Uh-huh.
以及Maso Pescatore和他的意大利黑帮
And Maso Pescatore ran the Italians.
帮派火拼 针锋相对
It was tit for tat.
这是波士顿历史上最危险的一年
The deadliest year in the history of Boston.
White帮派派人烧毁运酒卡车
White's gang set fire to rum trucks.
然后一个为Maso卖命的家伙
Then a guy on Maso's payroll
不慎带了某个陌生女人一起回家
went home with a girl no one had seen before.
这场战争没有胜利者 局面简直糟透了
No winner. Just a lot of mess.
我不想参与White和他的战争
I wanted nothing to do
with Albert White and his war.
但选择权不在我的手上
But I didn't have a choice.
因为他的情人 就是我的“线人”
His girlfriend was my inside man.
我深深地爱着她
And I was in love with her.
如果Albert发现她要离开 她就是死路一条
He'd kill her if she tried to leave him
如果他发现我和她在一起 他杀死我们十次都不嫌多
and he'd kill us both 10 times over if he found out
we were together.
但被爱情冲昏头脑的我们变得愚蠢
But we were in love and we were stupid.
如果他不在城里 我们就会相聚
And every time he was out of town, we were together.
这样的计划天衣无缝
The fit was perfect.
他趁我没有防备的时候突然来向我寻仇
Get revenge on me, when I least expect it.
- 你只是在说傻话罢了
- 我没有
- You just keep saying stupid things.
- No, I don't.
我知道你想听我说什么 我可不是傻瓜
I know what you like to hear
'cause I'm no fool.
我可没那么傻
Like a book.
我可以跟你们一起坐吗
Mind if I join you?
抱歉 老头子 我们在等人呢
Sorry, father time, we're waiting for someone.
不要
No.
Emma 这是我父亲
Emma, this is my father.
Thomas Coughlin
Tom Coughlin.
爸爸 这是我的朋友 Emma Gould
Dad, this is my friend Emma Gould.
幸会 Gould小姐
Pleasure, Miss Gould.
我能坐下吗
Mind if I sit down?
Gould小姐 你是哪里人
Where are you from, Miss Gould?
多切斯特人
Dorchester.
不 我是问你到美国之前 很显然你是爱尔兰人
No, I meant before.
You're clearly Irish.
我妈妈的家庭来自柯克
All my mother's people are from Cork.
哦 是吗 她叫什么名字
Really? What's her maiden name?
- 我不知道
- 你不知道吗
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
我妈妈很早就去世了 所以--
She died. She's dead, my mum, so...
那么 你是做什么的
So, what is it you do?
这里真是个虚荣和炫耀的地方 对吧
It's a real swank place, this, isn't it?
我知道我儿子靠什么生活
I'm aware of how my son earns a living.
所以我估计你跟我儿子的相识
I can only assume that if you've come into
contact with him
不是在犯罪现场
it was either during a crime
就是在某些残暴之人聚集的场合
or in an establishment
populated by rough characters.
我的问题让你不舒服了吗
Are my questions making you feel uncomfortable?
我不明白你想说什么
I don't know what you're on about.
但是实话讲 我一点不在乎
And to be honest, I don't really care.
我想说的是 你是那种会和犯罪分子勾搭在一起的人
I'm on about you being the type of Lassie
who consorts with criminals.
我不在乎我儿子是不是犯罪分子
The fact that the criminal is my son
isn't the issue.
我儿子始终是我儿子 这一点不会改变
It is that my son is still my son.
现在他却和你这种
And I have feelings that cause me
自愿伴随在犯罪分子和危险人物左右的人一起
to question the wisdom of consorting with
the type of woman
让我怀疑他的选择是否理智
who knowingly consorts with criminals.
- 你听懂了吗
- 好了 爸爸 说够了没有
- Did you follow all that?
- Enough, dad. Enough. Okay?
我叔叔提到过一个拿钱替他卖命的警察姓Coughlin
My uncle mentioned a copper on his payroll,
name of Coughlin.
那是你吧
Is that you?
你说的叔叔是不是叫Robert
This uncle would be your uncle Robert?
人们都叫他Bobo 对吗
Who everyone knows as Bobo?
你说的那个警察的名字是Elmore Conklin
No, the police officer you refer to
is Elmore Conklin.
他在萨文丘警局
He's stationed in Savin Hill.
他收取Bobo这种非法帮派的保护费
He collects shakedowns from illegal establishments
such as Bobo's.
虽然我基本上不会拜访多切斯特
I rarely get over to Dorchester.
但是作为总警督
Still, as deputy superintendent
我对打击Bobo这种非法帮派还是很有兴趣的
I'd be happy to take a greater interest in Bobo.
我要去补个妆
I need to powder.
有这个必要吗
Was that necessary?
又不是我挑起来的争端 Joseph
I didn't start the fight, Joseph.
所以别怪我说了什么话把它结束
So, don't criticize me for how I finished it.
我当警察已经37年了
I've been a police officer for 37 years.
我学到的最重要的一件事 你知道是什么吗
If I've learned one thing above all, do you know
what it is?
又是关于什么伟大国家的老故事吗
This gonna be another yarn from the old country?
不是
No.
不管你做什么事 它们一定会报应在你身上
What you put out in the world will always
come back to you.
但它们总会出其不意
But never how you predict.
那当然 爸爸
I'm sure it doesn't.
因为无知而产生的自信
Unearned confidence of that about which
one is ignorant
总会太闪耀 让你盲目
always has the brightest glow.
我相信我已经赚得足够的自信了
I think I've earned enough.
她长得很美
She's quite easy on the eyes.
是的 没错
Yeah, she is.
当然除了外表 我不太明白你看中她哪一点
Apart from that, I fail to grasp
what you see in her.
你否定她 是因为她来自多切斯特吗
Because she's from Dorchester?
虽然这一点也没什么帮助 她父亲是个皮条客
叔叔杀了至少两个我认识的人
That doesn't help. Her father's a pimp.
Her uncle killed two men.
但我可以忽视那些 Joseph 如果她——
But I could overlook all that, Joseph,
if she wasn't--
她从来没有假装过跟自己出身不符的人
she just doesn't pretend to be something she's not.
也许真正的她还没醒过来呢
Maybe she's just asleep.
谢谢你来看我
Thanks for stopping by.
也许今天晚上你应该跟他睡一个被窝
Maybe you should climb under
his covers tonight.
什么
What?
他贬低我 好像我是垃圾一样
He looks at me like I'm trash.
好像我们家人都不是人一样
We're not people.
我们只是多切斯特的Gould家
We're just the Goulds from Dorchester.
我们只配给你家织窗帘上的蕾丝
We tat the lace for your fucking curtains.
上帝啊 不要这么说
Jesus! You know what--
别他妈碰我
don't fucking touch me.
我整个人生都在目睹你父亲这样的人
My whole life, I got the high hat
and the icy mitt...
他们的高礼帽和冰冷的手
From people like your father.
我们并不比你们差
We're not less than you.
我没有这么说过
I never said you were.
但是他这么说了
Oh, well, he did.
管他呢
Fuck him, okay?
我爱你
I love you.
你以为爱情就这么容易吗
You think love's so easy.
我们可以让它就这么容易
It can be.
哦 上帝
Oh, god.
- 过来
- 我不要
- Come here.
- I don't want to.
- 别碰我
- 我很抱歉
- Leave me alone!
- I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 我想离开
- 好的
- I want to go.
- Okay.
好的
Okay.
您能赏点小钱吗
Can you spare two bits?
太感谢您了
Thanks a lot.
Joe Coughlin 有人让我来的
Joe Coughlin. I got an invitation.
把胳膊抬起来
Put your arms up there.
我得先检查一下
I gotta check you.
进去吧
Go ahead.
Joseph吗
Joseph?
是的 Joe Coughlin
Joe Coughlin. Yeah.
幸会
Pleasure.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
知道 所以我才应你的要求来到这里
I know enough to show up here when I'm asked.
我的名字叫Maso Pescatore
My name is Maso Pescatore.
我帮派的地盘是波士顿北端
I run the North End
还有南边佛罗里达州运来的私酒
and liquor coming up from Florida.
我呢——
I'm a man, uh,
我手上握着很多人的生死大权
with the power of other men's lives
in my hands.
但事实上
But the truth is, uh,
我只是个顽固的意大利老头而已
I'm just a simple wop from the old country.
现在 我唯一的仇敌
Today, my only true rival
就是Albert White
is Albert White.
解决掉他这个麻烦 我们就能
When that is no longer the case
停止这座城市里的斗争 杀戮和绝望
we can see an end to the fighting that has
plagued this town.
好吧
Well
我对你没有什么意见
I got no beef with you.
我只是不愿跟黑帮扯上关系
But I don't truck with gangsters.
哪怕是你这样风度卓群的大族长
Not even a sheik like you.
你犯下那么多的抢劫和偷窃
You do soup jobs and stickups
但却不认为自己是黑帮
but you're not a gangster.
- 那你觉得自己是什么
- 我也不知道
- What does that make you?
- I don't know.
大概是法外之徒吧
An outlaw, I guess.
我只是不想过黑帮的生活
I just don't want any part of that life.
发生在这个世界上的任何好事 或者坏事
How many things, good or bad,
come to us
有哪一件是我们想让它发生 就发生的呢
whether we ask for them or not?
比如说
For example,
我的一个手下看到你和一位年轻女士在一起
one of my men saw you with a young lady.
也许不叫“女士”更合适一点 一个情妇吧
Well, not so much a lady, but a  puttana moll
她的金主是Albert White
whose daddy's Albert White.
你想要的已经不再重要了
So, it no longer matters so much what you want.
你已经身处其中
You're in this life
你面前只有两条路
and it can only end two ways.
第一
One,
你抢在Albert White之前解决他
you get to Albert and put an end to him.
第二
Two,
我把我所知道的告诉White
I tell Albert about the girl.
让他为了他的情人解决掉你
And he gets to you first.
我已经说过了
Like I said,
我不是黑帮
I ain't a gangster.
我这辈子已经杀够人了
And I done enough killing in this life.
你想告诉White你听到的风言风语 随便
You wanna tell your enemy some rumor you heard?
Go ahead.
如果我杀掉Albert White
If I kill Albert White
他的位置会被另一个和他一样的人所取代
somebody's just gonna jump up
and take his place.
我却要与Pescatore帮派纠缠一生
And I'd be married to the Pescatore mob
for the rest of my life.
很早以前 我就不再亲吻大佬手上的戒指了
I stopped kissing rings a long time ago.
午安
Good afternoon.
你觉得他已经告诉Albert了吗
Do you think he told Albert?
如果告诉了 我早就死了
Nah. I'd be dead already.
上帝啊
Christ.
我们可以一起离开
We could leave.
去哪儿
Where would we go?
暖和的地方
Somewhere warm.
我哥哥Danny在加利福尼亚州
My brother Danny lives in California.
加利福尼亚州哪里
Where?
不知道 我们已经十年没说过话了
I don't know. I haven't talked to him
in 10 years.
他给我寄过明信片 说在当演员替身
He sent back a bunch of postcards saying
he was doing stunts
想要做编剧什么的
trying to be a writer.
上帝啊 我们可以去加利福尼亚州
God, I'd go to California.
不过提前跟你说 我可不懂什么正直的工作
I don't know much about honest work,
I gotta tell ya.
- 谁说我们要靠正直的工作活下去了
- 好吧
- Who said anything about honest work?
- Good.
我们可以为所欲为
No, we do what we wanna do.
想去哪就去哪
We'll go where we wanna go.
睡过整个白天
Sleep by day.
周六我在劳伦斯还有一票活儿
I got a job in Lawrence on Saturday.
之后我就自由了
And then I'll be free.
可以走了吗
Free to leave?
对 可以走了
Yeah. Free to leave.
我周六得去见那个--你知道是谁
I have to see you-know-who on Saturday.
- 让他去死吧
- 对 我也是这么想
- Fuck you-know-who.
- That's the idea.
别这样 你说怎么办 我也没得选
Oh, come on. What's the alternative?
你想让我被扔进查尔斯顿监狱吗
You want me to end up in the Charles?
周六我会跟他在Startler酒店见面
I'm supposed to meet him
at the Statler on Saturday.
他觉得让我看他和老婆亲热 是一件很兴奋的事
Turns him on to see me when his wife's on his arm.
在这之后他会到底特律去一周
After that, he's going to Detroit
for a week.
你结束之后 收拾一下 七点钟来酒店找我
Can you clean yourself up and get to the Statler
by 7:00?
我结束之后 收拾一下 七点钟来酒店找你
I think I can clean myself up and get
to the Statler by 7:00.
闭嘴
Shut up!
劳伦斯的这一票足以赚够我和Emma私奔去加州的路费
The Lawrence bank job would net us enough
to get to California on.
当时的我 就是在想这件事
It's true that's what I was thinking about.
我们走
Let's go.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
警察 警察来了
Copper. Copper!
噢 小心 小心
Whoa, look out! Look out!
操
Fuck!
让开路
Get out of the way!
啊
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
哦 操 妈的
Oh, fuck! Shit!
快点 他妈的让开路 快滚
Move! Get out of the fucking way!
Get out of the way!
警察
Cop!
好了 快下车 走走走 快点
All right, get out. Let's go.
Go, go, go!
快上车
Get in the car! Go!
妈的
Shit!
我走了半英里 偷到一辆车往北雷丁开去
I walked half a mile, stole a car in North Reading
又换了一辆在萨默维尔发现的道奇汽车
and replaced it with a Dodge
I found in Somerville.
我回到童年的老房子里  考虑着自己接下来的选项
I came back to my childhood home and
considered my options.
最新的报纸头条上 到处都是刚刚发生的一切
The story was in all the late editions.
三名死去的警察中有一名州警
The third dead cop was a trooper
在州际森林附近追上了逃逸车辆
who pulled someone over near the state forest.
那一定是Dion了
Had to be Dion.
继续往前走 这边有一台运货电梯
Keep going. There's a service elevator
up here.
我真不敢相信你真的来了
I can't believe you came!
- 我不来还能去哪儿呢
- 逃命啊
- What was I gonna do?
- Run.
- 逃到哪儿去
- 我不知道 出了这种事 人们都会这么做的
- Where?
- I don't know. It's what people do.
可我不会这么做
It's not what I do.
来吧
Come on.
妈的 该死
Shit! Shit! Shit!
你哭什么
Why are you crying?
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
那就笑一笑啊
Then smile.
我做不到
I can't.
不
No.
你如果死了
I'm sure as you die
肯定会告诉自己 你是因爱殉情
you'll tell yourself you did it for love.
不是的
No.
你只是对你自己所做的事心怀愧疚
You feel guilty about what you do
你这一生都在等人来惩罚你的罪恶
so you spend your life hoping someone will
punish you for your sins.
所以
Well,
我就来了
here I am.
Joe 真对不起
Joe, I'm so sorry.
她真抱歉
She's sorry.
我们都他妈觉得很抱歉呢
We're all fucking sorry.
把她带走吧
Take her out of here.
你答应我 你不会杀了他的
You said you wouldn't kill him.
Albert 我们说好了的
Albert, that was the deal.
- 跟你没关系了
- Albert 我不会带他--
- Don't worry.
- I would never have brought him here--
你觉得我会当众被你这样一个妓女侮辱吗
You think I'm going to be humiliated
by a whore?
有人告诉我
Someone comes to me
我的婊子在外面 和别的男人瞎搞
says some arsehole is putting horns
on my fucking head.
我没他妈把你的奶子切下来 再把你扔到垃圾堆里
算你幸运了
You're lucky I didn't cut your tits off and throw
you in the fucking dump.
- Donnie 带她上车去吧
- 不
- Take her to the car, Donnie.
- No!
Joe 对不起
Joe, I'm sorry!
Albert 不要杀她
Albert, don't kill her.
你还是担心接下来我要怎么收拾你吧
You should be more worried about what
I'm going to do to you.
Albert 不要杀她
Albert, don't kill her.
你何必关心她呢 她刚刚出卖了你
Fuck do you care? She just sold you
down the river.
求你
Please.
我对她说了谎
I wasn't honest.
我答应她如果她带你来见我
我就不会杀了你
I said if she delivered you to us,
I wouldn't kill you.
但我们都心知肚明 我必须要杀了你 Joe
But we both know I have to kill you,
don't we, Joe?
然后
And then,
我还要把她也杀掉
I'm going to kill her, too.
放开他
Leave him.
离开这里
Let's get out of here.
所以你现在杀警察了 对吗 Joseph
So you're a cop killer now, Joseph?
我没有杀人
I didn't kill anybody.
看起来 你的朋友准备带你走一趟死亡之旅
Looks like your friends were about to take you
on the dead man's drive.
爸爸 他们会杀了她的
Dad, they're gonna kill her.
我们不会杀你
Well, we won't kill you, Joseph.
只是我的同事想跟你聊聊
But some of my coworkers would like a word.
听着 求求你
Listen, please.
爸爸
Dad!
他们会杀了她了
They're gonna kill her.
她在Donnie Gishler的车上--
She's in the car with Donnie gishler.
我不知道这孩子的头是什么做的
反正不可能是普通的骨头
I don't know what his skull's made of,
but it isn't bone.
昏迷两周
In a coma two weeks.
没有颅内出血 没有记忆遗失 也没有语言障碍
No cranial bleeding. No loss of memory
or speech disability.
只是断了鼻梁和一半的肋骨
His nose and half his ribs are broken.
不过要到他不再排带血的小便 还得等一阵
进去吧
It'll be a long time before he doesn't see any blood
in the bowl. Go on in.
爸爸 她在哪儿
Dad, where is she?
找到她了吗
Did they find her?
我们跟踪了Donnie Gishler和她的车子
We followed her and Donnie Gishler.
他们在晚间九点二十分左右 掉进了海里
His car went off the road and into the ocean at 9:20.
贝弗利警局的一个警察潜水去找尸体
An officer from Beverly dove in looking for them.
什么也没找到 还因为体温过低住院一周
Ended up in the hospital for a week with hypothermia.
她是Albert White的情人
She was Albert white's girl.
她背叛了你
She betrayed you.
没错
She did.
然后呢
And?
我为她痴迷
I'm crazy about her.
痴迷并不是爱情
Crazy isn't love.
你自己十八年的婚姻都不是爱情
I saw your marriage for 18 years. It wasn't love.
对
No.
我知道那不是爱情
No, it wasn't.
无论如何 她已经死了
Either way, she's gone.
像你妈妈一样 上帝让她安息吧
She's as dead as your mother. God rest her.
他们在美加国境线十英里的圣阿尔邦抓住了Paulo
They caught up with Paulo in St. Albans about
10 miles from the border.
一队警察对他实施了追捕
A number of officers gave chase.
参加追捕的警察用14颗子弹结束了他的生命
He was struck by at least 14 rounds.
对于一个杀警察的凶手 还不够解气
Low for a cop killer.
Dion呢
What about Dion?
他可能已经逃过国境线了
It's possible he made the border.
你本应该是改进我和你母亲关系 拉进我们之间距离的幼子
You were the child that was supposed to fix the distance
between me and your mother.
你知道这一点吗
Were you aware of that?
我知道你和母亲之间有距离
I was aware of the distance.
人与人之间的关系不会改进的
People don't fix each other.
他们永远都不会为彼此做出改变
And they never become anything
but what they've always been.
我们能活在这个世界上 是因为运气
All we get sometimes is a little luck.
不要把你的运气浪费在对已经死去的女人的渴望上
Don't waste yours pining for a dead girl.
你自己决定自己的运气
You make your own luck.
有时是这样
Sometimes.
有时候运气能决定你的命运
Sometimes it makes you.
如果他认罪的话
If he pleads guilty
我能让他免于死刑
I can take the death penalty off the table.
三年牢狱 二十年缓刑
Three years served, 20 probation.
三年怎么可能
Three years?
这是三个警察的命案啊
There are three dead police officers.
又不是他杀的人
And he didn't kill them.
虽然他是总警监的儿子
He may be the son of a deputy superintendent
但是 他一定
but he will long know the inside
要去查尔斯顿监狱服刑的
of the Charlestown prison, I promise you.
我只是个小督查
Chief inspector.
我昨天被贬职了
I was demoted yesterday.
那该说的我也不用说了 你也别做梦了
Then we can leave unsaid the notion I was going
to dispel for you.
我没有做梦
I have no illusions.
我只不过是个实际的人
I'm a practical man.
照片上是后湾区的排房
The photograph is of a door
to a row house in back bay
是你和那个墨西哥年轻男孩约会的地方
where you have been keeping time with a young man
of Mexican descent.
如果你胆敢更改你们的私通的地点
If you move the location of your liaisons
我一小时内就会知道
I will know within the hour.
我会想想办法
Let me see what I can do.
我不管你想什么办法
Seeing what you can do is of little interest to me.
我被法庭宣判持械抢劫罪名成立
I pled guilty to abetting armed robbery...
将在查尔斯顿监狱服刑三年零四个月
And was given three years and four months
in the Charlestown prison.
如果父亲能再坚持两周的生命
If my father had lived two more weeks
我就能来得及出狱跟他道别
I could have said goodbye.
我拥有这注定的命运
I got one guaranteed life
我决定要好好过下去
and I was gonna live it.
我要利用Maso和他与Albert的恩怨
I would use Maso and his hatred for Albert
作为开始的棋子
to get me started.
事情变成这样 也挺有趣的
Funny how things change.
之前你在我面前侃侃而谈 说自己不做黑帮
What happened to all the talk
about not being a gangster?
而现在你又来找我 要求工作的机会
Now you come to me looking for a job.
我什么都没有了
I got nothing left.
我不愿做黑帮
I don't wanna be a gangster.
但是如果这个帮派能帮我扳倒Albert White
我愿意为其效力
But I'll work for one if I can get to Albert White.
从我在监狱听说的来看
From what I heard in prison
你还是想要Albert死的
you're still the man to see about that.
我们已经把他逐出了波士顿 你可能也听说了
We ran Albert White out of Boston, like you heard.
现在他正在佛罗里达州中部经营私酒生意
Now, he's making a run to our rum operation
in central Florida.
他想掌控坦帕市
He wants Tampa.
确实 我很需要人
It's true, I could use someone
需要一个想让他不再死灰复燃的手下
who is committed to putting an end to Mr. white.
我就是你要找的人
Then you've found your man right here.
你要永远把Pescatore家族放在第一
Your duty would always have to be
自己的事放在其次
to the Pescatore family first and yourself second.
你能接受吗
You live with that?
可以
Sounds fair.
我需要我的老帮手 Dion Bartolo
I just need one guy, Dion Bartolo
from my old crew
帮忙将一切打理妥当
to help me go down there and set up.
你能有个信得过的人 很不错
It's good to have someone you can trust.
佛罗里达的天气热得很
It's hot down there.
没关系 我不怕热
I don't mind hot.
你可从没经历过那种炎热
You ain't never felt hot like this hot.
我刚从查尔斯顿监狱出来 暖和一点挺好
I spent some winters in Charlestown.
I could use a change.
你到了坦帕市 要把我们的毒品生意建立起来
And get the narcotics running.
Starting in Tampa.
但是Frank Ormino现在管理着坦帕
Frank Ormino runs Tampa.
他决定不想面对这种令人头痛的局面了
He's gonna decide he doesn't need the headache.
什么时候决定的
When's he gonna decide that?
你到坦帕后十分钟 他就会决定了
10 minutes after you get there.
我明白了
I see.
- 如果我掌管了坦帕市 我们就是合作伙伴了吗
- 不
- Is that gonna make me and you equal partners?
- No.
Frank Ormino就是你同等的合作伙伴啊
Frank Ormino's an equal partner.
你看他又落得什么结果呢
But look what's gonna happen to him.
估计我是廉价劳动力吧
I guess I work cheap.
你不介意帮派里有爱尔兰人吗
Can you tolerate an Irishman in your crew?
在美国 我还见过更糟的呢
This is America. I've lived with worse.
我意识到 打破规则是不够的
I realized it's not enough
to break the rules.
你需要足够强大 来自己立定规则
You have to be strong enough to make your own.
嗨
Hi!
Joseph 啊
Joseph! Ah!
你好吗
How you doing?
- 看看你啊
- 看看你
- Look at you.
- Look at you!
关于你爸的事 很遗憾
Hey, sorry about your father.
你哥也是
Yeah, sorry about your brother.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Hey, thank you.
听着 当左撇子Downer在蒙特利尔找到我
Listen, when lefty Downer found me in Montreal
跟我说Pescatore让我跟他们干的时候
and told me the Pescatores wanted me to
come work for them
我以为他们要骗我还是咋的
I thought it was a straight bamboozle.
然后我又一想
Then I thought
这世上能把Pescatore这个魔鬼打动的人
一定是我的老搭档你啦
if anyone could charm the devil,
it's my old partner.
- 看哦 快看这车
- 哇 牛逼
- Look at this.
- Holy shit!
快看看
Would you look at this?
来 你先上
Here. After you.
别这么说啊
Get the fuck out of here.
我现在是你的马仔了 Joe Coughlin老板
I work for you now. Boss Joe coughlin.
去摸摸座位底下 有个好朋友等着你呢
Reach under the seat and you'll find a friend.
欢迎来到依伯城
这里是坦帕的有色人种聚居区
Welcome to Ybor, the Harlem of Tampa.
这座城市是建立在雪茄厂上的
Cigars built this place.
虽然现在你在空气中闻到的味道
What you're smelling now
有可能是蛋糕 也有可能是馅饼味
is probably bolos or empanadas.
坦帕市的其他地方都不和我们玩的
The rest of Tampa leaves Ybor alone.
在他们看来 我们只是一群
来自意大利和西班牙的脏鬼
As far as they're concerned,we're a bunch
of dirty spics and wops
只要不惹他们
and we can fuck off and
do what we need to do
他们才懒得理我们干嘛
as long as we leave them alone.
你会以为 大家都相安无事
You'd think we all get along
不过 实际上并没有这么平静
but it don't work out that way.
意大利人和古巴人都是自己玩自己的
The Italians and the Cubans
keep to themselves.
但是古巴人不喜欢西班牙人
But the Cubans, they hate the spaniards
而西班牙人又认为古巴人是一群自大和忘恩负义的黑鬼
and the spaniards look at all Cubans
like they're uppity coons
美国在一八九八年解放他们之后
尾巴都翘到天上去了
who forgot their place since America
freed them in '98.
不过古巴人和西班牙人都讨厌波多黎各人
The Cubans and the Spanish, they look down
on the puerto ricans
这里所有的人 每一个人都鄙视多米尼加人
and everyone, I mean everyone,
shits on the Dominicans.
意大利人只对白人毕恭毕敬
The Italians only respect you
if you came off the boat.
你们好 女士们
How you doing, ladies?
而美国白人觉得自己放个屁都有人关心
And the white people think anyone gives a shit
what they think.
你真厉害哟
You're a fucking piece of work.
这里是坦帕港口
Port of Tampa.
是谁呀
Who is it?
壁炉
Fireplace.
谢谢 J.T. 干得不错
Thanks, J.T. Good work.
整个城市有这样整整一套地下通道网络
There's a whole network of tunnels like this
under the city.
- 这个地下仓库是谁的
- 曾经是Frank Ormino的
- Who owns this warehouse?
- Frank Ormino did.
曾经是什么意思
What do you mean Ormino "did"?
Ormino几天前被打成筛子了
Ormino sprung a few leaks the other day.
这么快
That was quick.
看这边
Look at this over here.
花钱能买到的最好的设备
Best money can buy!
这东西得看好了 温度保持在华氏一百八十六度
You gotta keep it at 186 fahrenheit.
这就对了 这宝贝从不骗人
Yeah, these babies never lie.
不能让买酒的人酒精中毒死了啊
Like to keep people from dying when they
drink your hooch.
虽然我只会在监狱便池里酿酒
We made a lot of toilet booze in prison.
但我也知道要酿酒 你还缺两样东西吧
Looks to me like you're missing
two key ingredients.
- 是什么
- 工人 糖浆
- Which are?
- People and molasses.
对 我们有麻烦了
Yeah, we got a problem.
- 怎么了
- 是我们的供应商
- What?
- Our distributor.
他没有拿到货
He's been coming up empty.
怎么回事
What is it?
运货出了沉船事故
Boats have been sinking.
- 这家伙叫什么
- Gary L. Smith
- What's his name?
- Gary Ellsmith吗
- 不对
- Gary Ellsmith.
- No.
是Gary L. Smith 中间是缩写的大写字母
Gary L. Smith. It's a middle initial.
我也不知道为什么 他喜欢别人这么叫他
南方人的习惯
I don't know. He wants people to use it.
It's a Southern thing.
啊 难道不是混蛋的习惯吗
Not just an asshole thing?
也是
Both.
谢谢你 Roe小姐
Thank you, Miss Roe.
你们一定是Maso新的手下吧
You must be Maso's new find.
差不多吧 算是
I guess something like that.
- 你们好吗
- 很好
- How you doing?
- All right.
那么 你们来这里有什么事吗
So what brings you by?
我来是接管Frank Ormino的后事
I've been asked to take over
Frank Ormino's affairs.
我希望你们无需久留
I hope that's not permanent.
- 不好意思 我没有恶意
- 没什么 怎么了
- No offense.
- None taken. Why is that?
人们乐意和熟识的人做生意
Folks like dealing with who they know.
而不是像你们这样的生面孔
And nobody knows you.
哦 我明白了 那你说我们该跟谁做生意呢
I see. Well, uh, who would you suggest?
我没有什么野心
I have no ambitions for it
不过我可以考虑 跟你们做生意试试看
but to keep continuity,I might consider
doing it for a term.
之前三次我们找你运货 船都沉了
We're mostly concerned with why the last three
supply runs were hit.
是古巴人干的
That's the Cubans.
那再找一个新的供货商不就得了
Why don't you justgo to a new supplier?
- 没那么简单
- 为什么
- Not that simple.
- Why not?
因为这里所有供货商都要向Suarez家族进贡的
Because they're all paying tribute to
the Suarez family.
就是那个第七大街上开俱乐部的古巴人吗
That's the Cubans who own that club
down on 7th, right?
我们也会找他谈的
We're gonna need to talk to them, too.
呃
Uh,
你可能不知道 在这里我们是怎么办事的
I'm afraid you don't understand how
things are done here.
我直接和Suarez先生
I deal with Mr. Suarez
还有他的姐姐交易
and his sister.
好吧 明天晚上九点我们在他的俱乐部见面
Okay, I'm sure we can arrange a table for tomorrow
night about 9:00.
好极了
Great.
现在 Gary L. 你实话告诉我
Now, Gary L., tell me this.
你是直接为Albert White工作的吗
Do you work directly for Albert White?
又或者还有我们不知道的其他中间人
Or is there some intermediary I should
know about, as well?
- 什么
- 我们给瓶子做了标记
- What?
- We marked your bottles.
- 你们什么
- 所有酿的酒 我们都有标记
- You what?
- If you distilled it, we marked it.
所有那些应该在海运中丢失的私酒
And all these runs that were supposedly
lost at sea
全丢到Albert White的酒吧里去了
somehow made their way
into Albert White's speakeasies.
这你怎么解释
Can you explain that?
我不明白你什么意思
No. I don't understand.
我们来的时候 Dion载我经过了你家
Dion drove me by your house on
the way over here.
你家很漂亮嘛
You got a lovely place.
不过你得把这漂亮的家好好打包
You're gonna have to pack up all that shit
哪儿凉快滚哪儿去吧
and send it wherever it is you're going.
去哪儿
Where am I going?
你操过她吗
Are you fucking her?
什么 操谁啊
What? Who?
- 刚刚那位Roe小姐
- 你说什么
- Miss Roe.
- What?
- 肯定操过
- 毫无疑问了
- He's fucking her.
- Without question.
- 一定是操过了
- 拜托
- Definitely fucking her.
- Oh, come on.
下午在办公室细细品味她 早晨又--
Afternoon taste of Miss Roe--
算了 我不在乎你操谁
whatever. I don't care who you fuck.
这有几张车票
Here's some tickets.
晚上11点钟的车票
This is the 11:00 seaboard tonight.
我不管你带着谁走 但今天晚上你得赶上这趟火车
I don't care who you take with you, but you gotta
be on that train.
等一下 先生们
Wait a minute, gentlemen.
等等 咱们讲讲道理吧
Come on a second here. We could go through
the whole thing.
我可以直接放到你 让你的脑袋像个保龄球一样
在地上滚来滚去
I can bounce your head off the floor like
a fucking bowling ball.
但我们还是把事情搞得简单点
But let's just make it easy.
不然你自己登上那列火车 Gary L.
Put yourself on that train, Gary L.
要不然你就等着我们把你扔在铁轨上
Or we're gonna have to put you under it.
听着 我们--能不能好好--
Listen, I think... Could we...
拜托你们了 先生--
Now, come on, fellas. Gentlemen, can we...
大伙能不能坐下来谈谈--
Let's just sit and visit with each other.
Coughlin先生
Mr. Coughlin.
Francis Ormino中枪身亡
警察正在寻找目击证人
Roe小姐
Miss Roe!
你什么时候标记的瓶子
When did you mark the bottles?
你他妈说啥呢
Fuck you talking about?
自从我来了这里 你和我寸步不离
You've been with me every second
since I've been here.
你哪只眼见我标记瓶子了
See me mark any bottles?
对啊 所以我才知道你在里面说的都是胡话
No! That's how come I knew it was bullshit.
本人Dion Bartolo
Dion Bartolo.
我知道 这边请 Esteban先生已经等候多时了
Yes, of course. This way, please.
Mr. Esteban is waiting.
Suarez先生 幸会了
Mr. Suarez, nice to see you.
我给您介绍一下 这是Joe Coughlin
Let me introduce you to Joe Coughlin.
- 很高兴见到您 先生
- 我也是
- It's a pleasure to meet you, sir.
- Pleasure.
来喝一杯吧
Have a drink.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我从来就不认同古老的西班牙统治者所说的 私酒要越淡越好
I never agreed with the Spanish that the
lighter rums were superior.
但是我们古巴人还是照做了
Of course, we Cubans
went along
因为 古巴人认为无论什么都是越淡越好
because of our obsession that lighter is
greater in all things.
Dion Joesph  这是我的姐姐 Graciela
Dion, Joseph, my sister, Graciela.
- 很高兴见到你
- 我们已经见过了
- Nice to meet you.
- We've met.
抱歉是我记错了 当然 我们已经见过面了
My mistake. Of course, we have met.
是的
Yes, we have.
你好吗
How you doing?
你好 很高兴见到你
Hi. How are you? Nice to meet you.
上帝 这酒真不错
God, this rum is incredible.
如果能卖到北边去 那就太好了
Be nice if we could sell it up north.
等你们的国家把你们当成年人 让你们喝酒了再说吧
When your country treats you like adults.
不急 如果那样 我们这种人会失业的
No hurry. We'd be out of a job.
照片都是Esteban拍的
Esteban took those.
- 都是一些迈阿密的工人
- 拍得真棒
- The working people of Miami.
- Very good.
只是爱好而已
It is a hobby.
有空的话我可以给你拍肖像 Coughlin先生
Perhaps I photograph you some day, Mr. Coughlin.
算了 我这种人 还是照片越少越好
I don't know about that.
Fewer pictures out there of me, the better.
我同意印第安人说的
I'm with the Indians on that one.
说到摄魂——
Speaking of captured souls
我听说
I've been told
Gary L. Smith先生昨天晚上带着妻子登火车走了
that Mr. Gary L. Smith was seen boarding
the seaboard limited
带着妻子登火车走了
with his wife in one Pullman
还有他的所有家当
and he had that  puta maestra in the other.
这不好说
Oh, you never know.
有的时候换个环境对人很有好处的
Sometimes a change of scenery can do a man good.
所以你才来到依伯吗
Is that why you're here in Ybor?
想要换个环境吗
Little change of scenery?
我来依伯是为了酿制和贩卖私酒
I'm here in Ybor to distill and
distribute the demon rum.
但是现在因为你们不太正常的运货日程计划
我们有了点麻烦
A task which is made more difficult by your
erratic import schedules.
我们又不能左右海洋
We don't control the tides.
到迈阿密的船可是都不受海洋的影响呢
Tides have been fine from here to Miami.
迈阿密的事情我们可不知道
We know nothing of the boats to Miami.
Famosa先生知道 他告诉我们说
夏天这一带海域都是风平浪静
Senor Famosa assures me the tides have
been calm all summer.
既然你提到了Famosa先生的名字
And you say Senor Famosa's name
我们担心你会抢占我们的运输路线
so we worry you may overtake our supply routes.
不需要
No.
不需要 我提到他的名字只是想要跟你们表明
I use Senor Famosa's name to reassure you
从今往后 你们和我可以直接交易
that from now on, you can work directly with me
甚至可以提高价钱
and that you can charge me
a higher price.
- 我们能得到什么回报呢
- 你们可以得到
- What do we get in return?
- You get access
Ormino手下的警察和法官的保护 现在一切由我们控制
to Ormino's cops and judges, which we now control.
其中大多数的人也不会跟你们做交易
因为你们是古巴人
And most of whom wouldn't  do business with you otherwise
because you're Cuban.
你是想要我们糖浆的独家供货吗
And you would want exclusive
access to our molasses?
不需要 只要你切断Albert White的供货就可以了
Nope. You just can't sell to the White operation.
Albert White是一名让我们盈利的客户
Albert White is a paying customer.
他一直没给我们惹过麻烦
We've never had a problem with him.
我认识Albert White
I know Albert White.
我以为你们只愿意跟把你们当人看
I thought you might like to deal with someone
的客户做生意呢
who treated you like a human being.
这会引起流血事件吗
It is possible this will bring bloodshed.
当然会
This will definitely bring bloodshed.
我们提出的可是非常有利的条件
These are very favorable terms.
我们要只要Albert White
Albert White is what we get.
地方警长要见我们
The local sheriff wanted to see us.
这是种心照不宣的规矩
Apparently, it was a custom down there
在我们进行非法活动前
最好先跟他谈谈怎么违法比较好一些
to talk about how you were gonna break
the law before you did it.
警长人怎么样？
What kind of guy is the chief?
他是个条子 所以挺混蛋的
He's a copper, so he's an asshole.
除了这点 其他还可以吧
Beyond that, he's okay.
你干嘛 别乱动人家东西
What are you doing? Don't fuck with
the guy's stuff.
别让警长进门来看见个小混混动他文件
The sheriff's gonna come in to find some dago going
through his fucking papers.
看 Figgis警长长这样
Hey, this is Figgis right here.
请坐
Please, sit down.
我不想侮辱你们的智商
I won't insult you
所以就不问你们具体做什么生意了
by asking the nature of your business
你们也别撒谎来侮辱我的智商
so you won't have to insult me by lying.
可以吗
That fair?
我觉得可以
Sounds fair to me.
听说你是警监的儿子
It true you're a police captain's son?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你在海外服过兵役吗
You serve overseas?
是的 在法国
France.
向军队致敬
Tell it to the marines.
好的
Yes, sir.
军队里面给我们讲过这个
They told it to us.
我曾经也是一名士兵 然后又做了执法官
I was a soldier and then a U.S. marshal.
在我的人生中 我只杀过七个人
I've killed seven men in my lifetime.
实话说
Truth be told
直到今天 我还被关于他们的噩梦侵扰
their faces haunt me most nights.
把你们的生意范围控制在第二大街以北
You keep your business north of 2nd,
第二十七大街以南
south of 27th
内布拉斯加以东
and east of Nebraska,
你我之间就没什么分歧了
you and I will have little
in the way of discord.
好的
Sounds good.
我们生活在一个堕落的世界
I know we live in a fallen world,
虽然我呼吸着腐败的空气
but just because I breathe corrupt air
跟腐败的人们摩肩接踵
and rub elbows with corrupt men
但不要以为我也会随之变得腐败
never make the mistake of thinking
永远都不要幻想我会被你们腐蚀
that I am corruptible.
我不会犯这种错误的
I won't make that mistake.
好的
Right.
哦 抱歉 父亲 我以为只有你一个人的
Oh, dear, I'm sorry. Thought you were alone.
Loretta 没关系 这些先生正要走呢
That's all right, Loretta.
These gentlemen were just leaving.
亲爱的 你的礼仪呢
Honey, your manners.
哦 对 父亲
Oh, yes, father.
我是Loretta Figgis
Miss Loretta Figgis.
幸会 我是Joe Coughlin
Pleased to meet you, miss.
I'm Joe Coughlin.
我是Dion Bartolo
Dion Bartolo.
今天Loretta要坐火车踏上一段长长的旅程了
Loretta is taking the train
on a long journey today.
是要走了吗
It's going around.
- 她要去加利福亚州了
- 是吗
- California.
- Is that right?
她要去好莱坞 做电影明星了
She's gonna be a star in Hollywood.
只是一个试镜而已 爸爸
It's only a screen test, daddy.
一个银幕经纪人来了
A screen agent came here
挑中了几个姑娘
and picked out a few girls.
我哥哥就在那
My brother's out there.
他在好莱坞吗
Your brother's in Hollywood?
他说 他是个替身演员
He's a stuntman, I'm told.
就是那种从马上摔下来的人
Falling off horses.
很高兴见到你 Figgis小姐
Pleased to meet you, miss.
警长 再见
Chief.
先生们 再见
Gentlemen.
- 你吃香蕉不
- 不用了
- You're sure you don't want a banana?
- No, that's all right.
- 在波士顿你可吃不到这种水果
- 我知道 看着挺好吃的
- You can't get fruit like this in Boston.
- No, I know. It looks good.
- 哦 她在那边
- 什么
- Uh-oh. Here she is.
- What?
- 好的
- 你看好了啊
- All right.
- Just watch this.
你好 午安
Hello. Good afternoon.
- 你好吗
- 我很好 你呢
- How are you?
- I'm well. How are you?
我很好
Excellent.
你和你哥哥决定好了吗 关于我们的交易
You, uh, have you and your brother come to
any decision on our...
还没 我们仍然在考虑呢 Coughlin先生
Not yet. We're still considering, Mr.Coughlin.
好吧
Okay.
这对于我们来说将是非常重大的改变
Yes. It would be quite an upheaval for us.
当然了 我理解
I understand. Of course.
要做出改变可不容易
We don't make changes easily.
不过 一切都会改变的
Oh. There's all kind of change, you know.
我以前待的地方
Where I was recently staying
我们经常下国际象棋
we used to play chess a lot
每当你把你的卒子
and this is the kind of change where you
get your pawn
走到棋盘另一端
to the end of the board
把它变成皇后的时候
and it changes into a queen.
可不需要那么多深思熟虑
There's not a lot to think about here.
- 我会下象棋
- 是吗
- Yes. I do play chess.
- You do?
我父亲教过我
Yes. My father taught me.
大概你也记得 不管是兵还是王
And what you might do well to remember is that
the pawn and the king
最终都会回到同一个棋盒里
end up in the same box at the end of the game.
最终吗
The end?
我们没在讨论结束的时候
It's not about the end.
我们现在在讨论的是过程
It's about when you're playing the game.
结束的时候你可以把我吊起来 点火烧死
You could hang me upside down and light me
on fire at the end.
但是在下棋的过程中 我一定要赢
I wanna win while I'm playing.
我猜 大概你下过的棋 你都赢了吧
I have a feeling you win most
of the games you play.
还没有 但我打算赢呢
Not yet. But I plan on it.
要跟我一起赢吗
Why don't you join me?
知道吗 有人说私酒只是副业
You know, some people say liquor is only
your side business.
是这样吗
Is that so?
事实上
In fact
我听说 你们把转来的钱都捐出去了
I heard rumors you give most of your
money away.
都捐回古巴去了
A lot of it in Cuba.
你觉得这很蠢吗
And you think that's foolish?
我没有说蠢
Not foolish.
只是 这不是我的使命而已
It's just not my cause, that's all.
你的使命是什么
What is your cause?
在这里做私酒生意
The distribution of demon rum.
还有 一个人的生命不应该被他人左右
And that no man should rule
another man's life.
垄断了私酒市场 你就是国王了
If you corner the rum market, you will be a king.
还得对付Albert White
I'll still have to deal with Albert White.
我想知道 你要怎么使用你得到的权力
But how will you hold the power once you have it?
怎么 你觉得我不够强大吗
Why? You don't think I'm strong enough?
我觉得你不够残忍
I don't know if you're cruel enough.
而且 如果你很残忍的话
And if you are
我会很难过的
I will be very sad.
有权势的人不需要残忍
Powerful men don't have to be cruel.
但是他们通常都很残忍
But they usually are.
告诉我 你觉得高尚的人存在吗
Tell me something. Do you think there is
such a thing as a noble man?
我对高尚的人没有意见
I got nothing against noble men.
但是他们一般都活不过四十岁
They just rarely live past 40.
我父亲为古巴解放而死
My father died for Cuba.
母亲也因心碎死去了
My mother died of a broken heart.
他经常教导我和Esteban
He would often tell Esteban and I,
如果没有能够为之献出生命的信仰
"you cannot truly live
就不能算真正活过
"unless there is something for which you would die."
他听上去像个好人
He sounds like a good man.
他确实是好人
He was.
我们永远不会成为爱人的
We will never be lovers.
不会吗
No?
为什么呢
Why is that?
我不会爱上你的
We will not be lovers.
我们垄断了私酒市场 像国王一样享受生活
We cornered the rum market and lived like kings.
知道吗 行了 快点的
You know what? Fine. Come on, hurry up.
银行倒闭 工厂裁员
Banks collapsed.Jobs dried up.
但地下的罪恶
But vice, it seemed
对大萧条时代完全免疫
was depression-proof.
Suarez和Coughlin之间的合作关系
创造了难得的稳定收益
The Suarez-Coughlin partnership created a rare stability.
我们买通Albert在佛罗里达州中部的人
We paid off Albert's guys in central Florida
让他们停止武力抵抗
to put down their guns.
这样如果Albert White想要打击我们
他必须动用自己在迈阿密的人马
So when Albert wanted to hit us, he had
to use his Miami crews.
他的人一出现 我们就对他们发起丛林伏击
And when they showed up, we bushwhacked them.
Albert在迈阿密过着流亡的生活
Albert was living on the run in Miami
我们也掌控了佛罗里达州中北部所有的酒吧
and there wasn't a speak in central or north Florida
we didn't sell to.
找人来把火灭掉
Get something from in there and put this shit out.
好的
All right.
都给我趴下
Get on the floor!
现在 趴下
Get down, now!
趴下 趴地上
Get on the floor. Get down!
趴下
Get down! Get down!
天主教敢在我们的地盘卖私酒
This is what happens
就是这个下场
when catholics try to sell liquor down here.
这家伙的名字叫RD Pruitt
The guy's name is RD Pruitt.
好吧 那就去找到这人
Well, we'd better go find him.
他是三K党的人
He's in the Klan.
那又怎么样 全国有五百多万三K党
So what? So are 5 million other guys in this country.
三K党都有病
The klan has a lot of fucking juice.
不过是一群小学四年级就退学的杂种罢了
They're inbreds with fourth grade educations.
他们肯定爱死你了
Oh, they're gonna love you.
一个天主教徒 和有色人种工作 还和古巴女人同居
A catholic who works with coloreds and lives
with a Cuban.
RD的姐夫是个更大的麻烦
Bigger problem is RD's brother-in-law.
是谁
Who's he?
是Figgis警长
Chief Figgis.
我是Joe Coughlin
Joe Coughlin.
我不跟天主教徒握手
Don't shake hands with papists.
无意冒犯
No offense.
没事
None taken.
如果我告诉你 我虽然是天主教徒
却基本没去过教堂呢
Would it help if I told you I haven't been
to church in half my life?
好吧 是这样
All right, now.
RD
RD,
听说你在依伯惹了不少麻烦
word is you're causing trouble down in Ybor.
什么麻烦
How's that?
听说你总是袭击别人家的地方
Well, we hear you're sticking up places.
我可不知道怎么回事
I don't know a damn thing about that.
我就是跟你们玩玩
I'm just playing with you.
你们知道的吧
You all know that.
RD
RD,
这是位生意人 来做生意的
this is a businessman
who's come here to do business.
我建议你跟他做这笔生意
And I suggest that you do it with him.
他是个私酒贩子
This man is a bootlegger
和黑鬼通奸的人
and a fornicator with niggers.
他需要为此受到惩罚
He needs to be tarred and feathered
还做什么生意
not done business with.
哈哈哈 我只是玩玩
I'm just playing.
你开得起玩笑吧
You can take a joke, right?
当然 你随便开我玩笑
Sure, I can take a joke.
只要你不是别人的笑柄 对吧
Long as you don't become one, right?
听说你很喜欢我们的俱乐部Parisian
So you like the Parisian, right?
如果我就是喜欢呢
And if I did?
我可以让你分享俱乐部百分之十的收益
I might be able to cut you in on 10%
of the house take.
- 可以吗
- 当然
- You'd do that?
- I would.
好吧
Well,
我觉得百分之十可不够
I ought to be worth more than 10%.
那你说要多少
What were you thinking?
百分之六十吧
I was thinking 60.
市里最大的一家俱乐部
60%?
百分之六十的利润吗
The biggest club in town?
对啊
That's right.
凭什么
For what, exactly?
这样的话 我的朋友看你的眼光
大概会善意那么一点点
My friends might look on you more kindly.
- 什么朋友
- 我要百分之六十
- What friends?
- 60%.
孩子 我不可能给你百分之六十
Son, I ain't giving you 60%.
我不是你的孩子
I ain't your son.
我谁的孩子也不是
Ain't nobody's son.
你爸爸可算是松了一口气 不用丢脸了
Save your father some embarrassment.
- 你说什么
- 百分之十五
- What's that?
- 15%.
我打死你 你信吗
I will beat you to death.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你猜怎么着
You know,
我觉得百分之十五挺公平的 真的不能给我百分之二十吗
that does sound like a fair arrangement.
You go to 20?
我觉得对于一个不用出力工作的人
百分之五十是很公平的
I think 15's pretty good for a job you don't have
to show up to work for.
好吧
Well,
这个交易很公平
it's a fair deal
我很高兴能够达成这个协议
and I'm pleased to agree to it.
那么 我什么时候拿钱呢
How do I pick up my cut?
就在俱乐部里
Come by the Parisian.
每个月的第二个周二 晚上7点钟
Second Tuesday, every month, 7:00.
好的 幸会 Coughlin先生
Pleasure, Mr. Coughlin.
Irv 再会
Irv.
这算是谈成了吧
Sounds like we have a deal.
这孩子像个脑子稀烂的蠢葡萄
Boy's dumb as a grape.
我搞不懂Maso想要做什么
I don't understand what Maso wants.
失手被捕的几率降低了百分之七十
收入翻了三倍
Arrests are down 70%, revenue's up 300%.
我不喜欢他现在派一个蠢孩子来给我当监工
I don't like getting some kid sent down here
like we need supervision.
我们才不需要监工
No! We don't need supervision.
Digger只是来视察一下赌场的计划
和生意运行的情况
Digger wants to look at the casino option,
check progress, that's all.
再回去跟老大报告一下
He's gonna report back to the old man.
没什么 不要小题大做 Joe
It's a joke. Don't make a big thing of it.
他儿子跟他汇报的事情 尤其是赌场
Maso还是会听的吧
Maso's still gonna listen to what his son tells him
about starting a new casino.
别担心了
Don't worry about it.
他怎么叫Digger这个名字
How did he get the name "Digger"?
因为他就是个他妈的蠢货
Because he's a fucking dummy.
他在帮派里面就是给尸体挖坑的
All they let him do is dig ditches for
the bodies they bump off.
- 没骗人
- 没
- No shit?
- Yeah.
真好笑
That's great.
我提出一个投资赌场的计划
I'd come up with a plan to invest in a casino
就建在萨拉索塔
with stakeholders in Sarasota
的丽兹酒店工程地上
at the new Ritz development site.
丽兹酒店赌场
Ritz hotel and casino.
最高一层 A型的尖顶
Top shelf. A-one.
就是我们的赌场
...right to the casino.
最高级的娱乐场所
Absolute top-level resort.
不管你花不花钱赌博 都是非常好的度假体验
Extraordinary resort experience whether
you gamble or not.
建赌场是非常巨大的工程
For such a violent business
如果处理得当 我们将会为当地人提供数以百计的工作
it was populated with a surprising number of guys
让他们维持生计
who were just putting food on the table.
这些人里 却不包括Digger
Digger wasn't one of those guys.
就是这里
So this is it.
禁酒法案不会永远存在 对吗
Volstead act won't last forever, right?
私酒生意也不能永远做下去 禁酒结束了我们怎么办
What are we gonna do when prohibition ends?
当然是赌博
Gambling.
我们可以动用自己的人际关系 将赌博合法化
We use the connections we put together
to get it legalized.
然后这里就会成为唯一一家合法经营的赌场
And we're the only ones in place to run it.
就是这里吗
And this is it?
对 这里是丽兹酒店的地
It will be. Ritz longboat key.
上周我刚和萨拉索塔的人谈过
I sat down with the owners in Sarasota last week.
他们为什么要把这块地给我们
Why did they let us in?
因为他们没有能力经营赌场 没法将赌博合法化
Because they can't get gambling legal, and they
can't run a casino.
我们借他们的地 经营赌场
They own the property, we run the casino.
然后利润五五分成
We chop the profits 50-50.
等一等
Wait a minute.
我们有魔法棒吗 可以更改法律
Do we have a magic stick for changing laws?
我听说你已经把宾果赌博合法化了
I heard you got bingo legal.
是一步一步来的 首先得有先决条件——
It's a step. It's that prerequisite.
You gotta do one thing
- 然后你——
- 我知道了 就是那个先决条件嘛
- and then you get--
- Yeah, I know. It was a prerequisite.
你奶奶可以来这里玩 可以在教堂里玩
Your grandmother can come down.
She'll play in the church.
宾果
Bingo!
我们在塔拉哈西和萨拉索塔都有人筹集资金
Look, I got bagmen buying inspectors in
Tallahassee and Sarasota.
甚至有人在州议会和国税局游说爱赌博的成员
I got guys going after senators and
IRS agents who gamble.
如果我们能将赌博合法化
We get gambling legal
我们就能赚大钱了 还是合法的
we are rich. Legit.
而且这是个长久生意
For the long fucking haul.
这些我也会啊
I talk a good game, too.
不过我很喜欢你
But I like you.
这家伙可聪明了
He's a very smart boy.
Maso对赌场的点子很狂热
Maso went crazy for the casino.
每天都要打电话追踪进度 好像这主意
是他自己想出来的一样
Called every day for updates like it was his idea.
信封上的收信人是 Joseph Coughlin 操黑鬼的人渣
It was addressed to "sir Joseph Coughlin,
nigger fucker."
信的内容只有五个字
Inside was a two-word note
百分之六十
"sixty percent."
同样的信 同样的内容
Same note. Same message.
我们已经尽力了 这家伙有人罩着呢
We're doing everything we can, but he's protected.
他在这里扎根太深
His roots here are too deep.
那就把他的根挖起来呗
Well, time to start digging.
下午好 先生们 我是Virgil Beauregard
Afternoon, gentlemen. Virgil beauregard.
你们找我有什么事吗
What can I do for you today?
我们希望您能和RD Pruitt讲讲道理
We're hoping you can talk some sense into RD Pruitt.
还没见过多少人能跟那种人讲通道理呢
Ain't too many people ever had much success doing that.
我们这不来让您试一试吗
We'd like you to try.
为什么呢
And what would the reason be?
为了他的个人安危
His self-preservation.
他需要停止袭击我的俱乐部
He needs to stop shooting up my clubs.
俱乐部吗
Clubs?
什么俱乐部 桥牌俱乐部吗
What kind of clubs? Bridge clubs?
因为我就是老坦帕扶轮社的成员
Because I belong to the greater tampa
rotary club myself
我不记得曾经见过你这张脸啊
and I don't recall ever seeing you.
我们来这里跟你谈正事
I come here to do a piece of business with you
你就准备耍我们玩吗
and you wanna play fucking games?
- 你认为我在耍你们玩吗？
- 听着
- Is that what I wanna do?
- Look,
你是这里三K党的大法师
you're the grand wizard of the ku klux klan
around here.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
但你觉得我们能有今天的地位
But do you think that we got where we are
是因为让你们这群愚蠢的混蛋踩在我们头上吗
by letting some inbred shit pickers muscle us?
如果你认为我们是愚蠢的混蛋的话
那你可是犯下致命大错了 孩子
If that's who you think we are, you're making
a fatal miscalculation, son.
因为我们管着金钱和银行
'Cause we're clerks and bankers
管着所有的警察
and police officers and deputies and...
甚至手下还有一名法官
Hell, we even got a judge.
如果你没有足够的能力对抗我们
And if you're dim enough to fight us
我们会将地狱之火降临到你
we're gonna rain bloody hellfire down on you
和你所爱的人身上
and all you love.
这么说 你是用比你更有权势的人威胁我 对吗
So you're threatening me with people who are
more powerful than you?
没错
Exactly.
那我还跟你说个屁啊
What the fuck am i talking to you for?
什么风把你吹来我家了
You've come to my home.
省得你大动干戈地抓我过来了
Thought I'd save you the trouble of hauling me in.
七十五名证人
75 witnesses.
没有一个愿站出来的
Not a one will come forward.
来瓶啤酒吗
You want a beer?
跟啤酒差不多 但也不差
It's near beer, but it ain't bad.
好啊 来一瓶
I'd love one.
谢了
Thanks.
警长 我需要和RD见面
I need RD, chief.
我就知道你会这么说
I expect you'd feel that way.
你知道如果不帮我的话 会造成什么后果吗
You know what happens if you don't help me.
不 不知道
No. I don't.
更多的尸体会堆积成山
More bodies are gonna pile up.
今天雪茄城屠杀那样的事件会接连登上头条
More articles like "cigar city slaughter"
are gonna get written.
你也会被清除掉
And the chief's gonna get pushed out.
你呢 也会
You, too.
也许吧
Maybe.
不同的是 当你被“肃清”时
Difference is, when you get pushed out
会是被来自耳后的子弹打穿后脑
someone does it with a bullet to the back
of your ear.
我不会再出卖我的妻弟了
I'm not selling out my wife's brother.
我不想这么做
I don't wanna do this.
做什么
Do what?
不想做你逼我做的事情
I don't wanna do what you're making me do.
我没有逼你啊
I'm not making you do anything.
你有
Yeah, you are.
怎么
What?
她没去成好莱坞
She didn't make it to Hollywood.
只是流落在洛杉矶而已
She just made it to Los Angeles.
这不是真的
That's not right.
我们给她找了个专科的医生
We got her witha special doctor now.
她已经没事了
She's all right.
什么样的医生？
What kind of doctor?
帮人们戒掉海洛因的医生 Irv
Kind that gets people off heroin, Irv.
永远不许直呼我的教名
You do not ever call me by my Christian name.
我们谈话时 无论何年何月
You'll call me chief figgis
你只能叫我Figgis警长
for whatever years or days remain in our acquaintance.
你明白了吗
Are we clear?
她现在这样 不是我害的
I didn't do this to her.
请告诉我
You just name your price
我要做什么 你才肯告诉我我女儿在哪
for telling me where my daughter is.
她现在在一个干净又安全的戒毒中心
She's in a clean, safe facility
我还不打算告诉你在哪 直到——
and I'm not gonna tell you where she
is until you...
直到什么
Until?
RD 你得跟那小子见一面
Rd, you are gonna meet with this boy again
就谈这件事 这会是最后一次见面了
and there ain't another discussion to be
had on the matter.
对 就咱们俩
Yeah, it'll just be the two of us.
在丽兹酒店那块地
Longboat key by the ritz.
今晚十点
Tonight at 10:00.
我什么时候才能知道女儿的具体地址
When do I get her location?
如果我跟RD见面后活着回来 就告诉你
Soon as I get out of this meeting alive.
请你亲自动手
You do it yourself.
什么
What's that?
如果你要杀他的话
If you're gonna kill him
拿出真男人的勇气来 亲自扣下扳机
be man enough to pull the trigger.
让你的手下杀人是耻辱 你太软弱 连扳机都不敢扣
Ain't no pride in having other people do what you're
too weak to do yourself.
好的
Okay.
据我所知 扣下扳机没有那么难
In my experience, it doesn't take much
to pull a trigger.
你好 RD
Hey, rd.
我姐夫呢
Where's my brother-in-law?
他没跟来
He didn't come.
小子们
Boys,
这位可很厉害的
this one here is rat tricky.
一枪就把你眼珠子打出来
Take your eyes off that peashooter
我跟你保证 你绝对斗不过他
I promise it'll be in his hands.
行吧
Not likely.
你说话算话吗
You a man of your word?
要看是对谁了
Depends on who i give it to.
那么你不是像我要求的那样一个人来的咯
So, you ain't come alone like I ordered?
妈的 倒被你看穿了 没意思
Shit, rd, that would spoil the fun.
人都在哪呢
Where they at?
你知道吗 这可能是禁酒令结束后
You know, this could be the biggest casino
in the United States
整个美国最大的赌场
when they end prohibition?
如此虔诚的国家 禁酒是不会结束的
They ain't gonna end prohibition in
a god-fearing country.
整个国家都要完蛋了
Country's in the tank.
银行和城市破产
Banks going under, cities are bankrupt.
因为我们选了个共产党当总统
Because we got a communist president.
因为我们没有了贩酒的税收
Because we're not taxing liquor.
所以政府一定会立法将赌博合法化
And that's why the state's gonna change its laws
to legalize gambling.
说不定你能跟我们一起干
And you could be part of that.
我不想跟你一起干
I don't wanna be a part of nothing with you.
他给你多少钱
How much is he paying you?
谁
Who?
Albert White
Albert white.
他给你多少钱 让你袭击我的酒吧和俱乐部
How much is he paying you to shoot up my speaks?
你真是他的好狗腿
Because you're doing a hell of a job for him.
好吧 我是拿了他的臭钱
Yeah, I took his catholic money.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
不给钱我也给他做
Because I'd have done it for free.
你是一条害虫
You are a pestilence.
你和你的黑鬼古巴妓女
You and your nigger whore girlfriend
还有意大利流氓哥们儿
and your dirty dago friends.
我要抢走你的俱乐部
I'mma take the Parisian.
这次不要百分之六十
Not 60%.
我要百分之百
The whole thing.
我要把你所有的俱乐部都收了
I'mma take all your clubs.
我要夺走你拥有的一切
I'mma take everything you got.
大概还会顺便路过你家
Might even go by your house
操你那个黑鬼女人 再把她喉咙割开
tear off a piece of that nigger girl before
i cut her throat.
你可能还不明白我说的话
You ain't got this yet
你要滚蛋了
but you leaving town, boy.
连行李都没来得及收拾
You just forgot to pack your bags.
好吧
All right.
上吧
Go ahead.
操
Fuck.
哦 糟糕
Oh, shit.
坏了
Shit.
把车开过来
Bring the car around.
好了
All right.
- 我们马上带你去找医生
- 妈的 疼死了
- We'll get you to a doc.
- Fuck. It hurts.
知道 没事 疼不死你
Yeah. It hurts, but it's not gonna kill you.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
我不应该给他看那些照片的
Oh, fuck. We should have never shown him the pictures.
- 什么照片
- 给Figgis看的照片
- What pictures?
- Figgis.
为了把这混蛋解决掉 你没有别的选择
That's what we had to do
to put this fucking guy down.
代价太高昂了
Price was too high.
我怎么觉得是你开枪打伤我的
I think it was you who shot me.
- 啥
- RD还没来得及开枪就被我干掉了
- What?
- I got him before he got a shot off.
- 咋成了我了
- 那能是谁呢 不可能是别人
- It wasn't me who shot you.
I- t couldn't have been nobody else.
- Fasani在另一边呢
- 对啊 就是该死的Fasani打伤你的
- Fasani was back there.
- It was Fasani who fucking shot you.
不对 Fasani是从后面过来的
No, Fasani was coming from back there.
- Fasani在后面 他——
- 对啊 Fasani后边来的 向这里开枪
- Fasani came over here.
- Fasani was back there shooting this way.
他从这个角度打伤你 就是这里
He came on this angle like this. Right here.
我一直在这边呢
I was over here.
- 我干掉了这些个混蛋
- 就是你打的啦
- I got these motherfuckers.
- You hit me!
- 快把车开过来
- 好的
- Ah. Just get the fucking car around.
- All right.
这里会建成一个很棒的赌场
It's gonna be a great casino.
- 是吧？
- 对
- Right?
- Yeah.
Albert自己出钱 买通RD让他干掉我们
Albert had been paying rd on his own
to come after us.
可是我们杀掉了一个三K党成员
But once we killed members of the klan
三K党可真的要寻仇的
the klan took it personal.
他们来医院想刺杀我
They came to finish me off at the hospital
但我们在门口配了守卫轮流值班
but we had guards posted at the doors.
当三K党放弃刺杀启程回家时
When the klansmen gave up and went home
Dion就悄悄跟上了他们
Dion had them followed.
一系列的殴打 爆炸和谋杀
The subsequent string of beatings, bombings
and murders
有效地震慑并结果了坦帕的三K党
effectively put an end to the power of the kkk in tampa.
- 你感觉如何
- 我很好
- How do you feel?
- I'm all right.
是吗
You are?
谢谢
Thank you.
Irv的妻子带着他的儿子离开了他
Irv's wife moved out and took their son with her.
人们也一整季都没有见过Loretta
No one saw Loretta for the whole season.
我能姓你的姓吗
Can I take your name?
你想结婚吗
You wanna get married?
什么
What?
我们已经算是结婚了 不是吗
Well, we are married, aren't we?
Graciela Isabella什么的——
Graciela Isabella...
我记不住你那么长的名字 Lunes Martes什么的
I can't remember them all. Lunes, martes...
- 别闹 我没有那么长的名字
- 等等
-  Estupido! I don't have that many names.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Graciela Coughlin
Graciela Coughlin.
能配上你的名字 是我的荣幸
Best thing that ever happened to that name.
我买了几栋楼
I bought buildings.
是吗 我们刚刚才结婚  你就已经开始买房了
Wow! We're married and, just like that, now you
bought some buildings?
是的 我在Perez工厂附近买了三座楼
Yes. I bought three buildings
by the Perez factory.
你买这些楼做什么
What are you gonna do with these buildings?
我想用它们做流浪妇女儿童的收容所
I want to give shelter to abandoned women
and their children.
这很重要 Joe
It's important, Joe.
你的古巴政治信仰呢
What happened to Cuban politics for a cause?
我爱上了你
I fell in love with you.
你就限制了我的德行
You restrict my mobility.
过来
Come here.
我爱你
I love you.
消失了几个月后
After months of seclusion
Loretta再次出现了 她几乎只穿白色
Loretta emerged from home and declared she would
only wear white.
声称为她做出决定的是上帝
A decision made for her by Jesus Christ
她的贞操将只为上帝保留
to whom she would now be wed.
被诅咒的行业
Damnable business.
她的布道大受欢迎
Her show was a hit.
她为坦帕展望的愿景 是洗清罪恶的城市
And her vision of tampa, cleansed of sin
当然不能有赌场了
didn't include a casino.
那个布道的是怎么回事
What's the problem with this preacher?
没怎么回事
There's no problem with the preacher.
一切都会顺利进行的
Everything's gonna work out fine.
不要让任何事情阻挡赌场的建立
Nothing can jeopardize our casino deal.
当然 Maso 那是肯定的
Absolutely, maso. 100%.
一定要尽你所能
Do what you need to.
我可以去她的布道场 跟她谈谈
Look, I'm gonna go down there. I'm gonna talk to her.
需要我做的事情 我会做好的  好吗
Whatever needs to be done will get done, okay?
把问题都给我解决了
Just make sure the problem goes away.
别再让我听见这些事
I don't want to hear about it.
好的 非常感——
All right. Thanks a lot.
你没必要偷听电话
You don't need to listen in on me.
对我的工作有什么疑问 你就问我
Ask me anything you wantabout my business
我会告诉你的
I'll tell you.
这是你的事 与我无关
It's your business, not mine.
随便问吧 我会告诉你的
But I will. I'll tell you anything
you wanna know.
好的
Yeah.
我刚来到这里的时候
I came down here, it was all about
是为了复仇 为了赚钱
getting revenge, making money.
而现在 我所做的一切
Now, everything I do, every step I take
都是为了你和我 为了保护我们的未来
is about you and me and protecting our future.
你必须明白这一点
And that's what you need to understand.
这一切正在一点点侵蚀你
But if those steps make you
将你变成另外一个人
even little by little, someone else
你已经不是你自己了
then you will not be you anymore.
你就是你 虽然你做过很多坏事
You're you, except for all those bad things you did.
现在的你已经改变了
You're almost you.
我想要的是真正的你
I want the real you.
我就是我
You have me.
你拥有的就是真正的我
You have me. Come here.
你已经拥有我了
You have me.
赌博摧毁灵魂
Gambling destroys the spirit.
阿门
Amen.
我们都听说过
One hears much
关于个人的自由和解放
of personal Liberty.
但当你见识到野蛮的人性
But when you've seen the barbarity of man
被这些野蛮的人性侵蚀
and been treated to personal doses...
你们看
You see,
这就是赌棍所要求的自由
it is simply Liberty for the gambler.
赌棍们消费着上帝赐给他们的自由
For the gambler to fritter away the gifts of god
用来满足自己的私欲
using it for himself.
阿门
Amen.
个人的自由
Personal Liberty
就这样
is the Liberty
成为了加害于人的凶手
of a murderer.
引诱着你
A seducer!
成为一头藏在羊皮之下的恶狼
A wolf
藏在羊皮之下的恶狼
who wants to remain in a sheepfold.
我要提出一个问题
I ask you
你的美德有多廉价
how cheap is your virtue?
不廉价 一点都不廉价
No! Not cheap! Not cheap.
你的美德有多廉价
How cheap is your virtue?
不廉价
It's not!
我的美德一直都很廉价
My virtue's always been pretty cheap.
你有什么美德啊
What virtue?
他们居然
And they seek to build a house of gambling
要在我们的码头建赌场
on our waterfront!
不行
No!
但我们居然默许了
But we acquiesce.
告诉你 要解决她 只有一招
I'll tell you, there's only one way
to deal with it.
如果她在的话 民众就不会支持赌场建立
With her around, the casino gets voted down.
没有赌场的话
The casino gets voted down
- 咱俩就要倒霉了
- 我会处理的 好吗
- me and you are on the hook for it.
- I'll handle it, okay?
- Coughlin先生
- Figgis小姐
- Mr. coughlin!
- Miss figgis.
谢谢你今天给我机会见面
Such a pleasure. Thanks so much for seeing us.
布道很精彩
It was a great show today.
真是太棒了
Great. Terrific.
您认识我父亲吧
And you know my father.
警长
Chief.
这是Mayweather先生
And this is Mayweather.
他在南方讲学布道
Mayweather's taking the good word and preaching
it down south.
幸会 先生
It's a pleasure, sir.
幸会 你做得很好 迈阿密人确实需要听听道
My pleasure. That's good. They need to hear
about this in Miami.
- 继续努力
- 我会努力的 先生
- Keep up the good work.
- I'll try, sir.
很好
Great.
您有什么事吗
What can I do for you?
我想跟你单独谈谈
I was hoping I could just have a word
with you for a second.
我希望——
I was hoping to, uh,
能跟你谈谈丽兹酒店赌场的事
talk to you a little bit about the ritz.
我父亲说 你曾经是个好人
My father says there once was a good man in you.
我不知道 我现在就不是好人了吗
I wasn't aware he'd departed.
你为这里的人民做了很多
You do quite a lot for the people here.
但我们都知道 你这些善举
But we both know your good works are mitigated
在你肮脏罪恶的目的之前 微不足道
by your evil deeds.
是吗
We do?
你非法从别人身上榨取利润
You profit from the illegal addictions of others.
利用他们成瘾的嗜好 弱点 懒惰和淫欲
Their weakness and sloth and libidinous behavior.
但你可以解脱自我的
But you can free yourself of that.
可我不想
But I don't want to.
怎么会不想呢
Of course, you do.
Figgis小姐 你是位漂亮的姑娘
Miss figgis, you're a lovely woman.
你的故事很精彩
And your story is amazing.
我丝毫不奇怪 你的听众会在这几天内翻三倍
I'm not surprised the flock's up threefold
since you started here.
其实翻了五倍
More like five times.
在禁酒的十年里 人们消费的酒 比过去哪一年都多
More booze has been drunk in the last
10 years than ever before.
因为人们不想被强制禁酒
Because people don't wanna be told they can't do it.
通奸也是同样的道理
The same could be said of fornication.
人们都想通奸
People want it
但是不想被强制禁止
but don't want to be told they can't have it.
当然不想了
Well, nor should they.
抱歉 你说什么
I'm sorry?
人们想要通奸 干嘛要阻止他们
If people want to fornicate, I see
no reason to stop them.
如果他们想与动物通奸呢
And if they wish to lie down with animals?
真的吗
Do they?
怎么
I'm sorry?
人们想和动物通奸吗
Do people wish to lie down with animals?
有些人想
Some do.
如果都像你这样 他们的罪恶就会传染
And their sickness will spread if you have your way.
原谅我 我看不出兽交和禁酒有什么关系
Forgive me. I see no correlation between alcohol
and lying down with animals.
它们都是罪恶
There's a correlation across all sin.
都违抗了上帝的意愿
It is all against the wishes of god
因此都是不能被容忍的
therefore, all equally offensive.
容我道个歉 我可能说错了话
Let me apologize. I think we got off on the wrong foot here.
我只是想请求你
I'm just here to ask you
如果你愿意在你的布道中
if you would be amenable to omitting
略去赌博和赌场的部分
the casino issue from your sermons
为表感谢
and in exchange
我们会带来广大的商业机会
we're gonna bring a business here.
和无数的工作岗位
Business will create jobs
这大概能抵消这里随贫穷而来的罪恶
which will reduce the sinfulness
扶助贫困 分配闲散劳动力
that comes with poverty and idle hands.
我们也会支持教堂
We'd be willing to contribute to the church.
甚至乐意帮您建造几座教堂
Hell, we'd be willing to build a few churches.
如果上帝改写了圣经 将赌博写在罪恶之外
If god rewrites the Bible to cast gambling
as virtuous
我很乐意改写自己的布道内容
I will refrain from speaking against it.
但到目前为止
But until then
我们并没有资格去决定什么是罪 Coughlin先生
we don't get to pick our sins, Mr. coughlin.
我做不到
I can't do it.
什么
What?
她会毁掉我们的整个计划  你却说你做不到
She's gonna fuck up the whole deal. What do you
mean you can't do it?
我知道 我只是伤害不了她
I know. No one touches her.
这是个错误
That's a mistake.
我知道
No shit.
你们想喝点什么吗
Can we get you anything?
不用了 谢谢
Oh, we're okay. Thanks.
我知道你们都很忙 也不想浪费你们的时间
We know you men are busy and we don't want
to waste your time.
我们不会投资丽兹酒店的赌场了
We're not going to invest in the casino at the ritz.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
恐怕我得说是了 公众反响太严重了
I'm afraid so. The publicity is too much.
就因为一个在他妈的帐篷里布道的女人吗
One woman preaching in a fucking tent?
是的 因为赌场占了我们百分之二的股份
Yes, because the casino would represent only 2%
of our total holdings.
你们是让虔诚的白人基督徒女孩染上毒瘾的爱尔兰人和意大利天主教徒
And we can't appear to be a company of Irish
and Italian catholics
我们不能让这种人代表我们的企业
turning white protestant girls into drug addicts.
我的老板不会欣赏你的决定的
The people I work for are gonna be very upset about this.
我们不会被打倒 或者被欺骗
We aren't men to be muscled or conned.
我们是事业机构 你不能贿赂或恐吓我
We're an institution. We can't be bribed or bullied
因为我代表的
because I simply represent the vested interest
是政府高官的投资意向
of a board of governors.
我们是这个国家的白人地主贵族
We are the landed white gentry in this country
并不想割让出一块
and we have no plans to carve off a strip
of this country
我们历尽艰辛 才夺下并殖民的土地
which we have gone to great pains
to break and colonize
把她交给天主教徒 犹太佬  黑鬼
and hand it over to catholics, Jews, darkies
或者意大利佬
or dagos.
这只不过是一场更大更吵的集会而已
It's just a bigger, better racket. That's all.
钱在你我这样的人手中流来流去
Keeping the money in your hands and out of the
hands of people like us.
所有你提到过的那些人
All those people,
那些黑鬼们
the negro
你们踩着人家的脊背建立的国家
on whose back you went to great pains
to break this country
那些移民 一穷二白
and the immigrants who came over here with nothing
拼着命工作 真心相信着
and worked their fingers to the fucking bone,
all believed it
你们所说的 人人都可以功成名就的鬼话
when you told them they could get ahead.
我可能活不到那么久
And one day, and I may not live to see it
但是他们总有一天会想明白的
they're gonna figure it out.
我告诉你 到那时候
But I tell you what. I'd hate to fucking be you.
我可不想像你一样 夹在这群人
Standing between those people
和他们应得的命运之间
and what they deserve.
祝你好运 混蛋
Good luck to you. Prick!
本来可以建个好赌场的
Would have been a hell of a casino.
没关系 你还有机会
You'll get another chance.
事情总会峰回路转的
Things swing back around.
并不是所有的事都会峰回路转
Not all things.
我们回去的路上 听到了广播里的消息
They announced it on the radio just when
we got back.
刚刚竞选成功的富兰克林·罗斯福总统
President-elect Roosevelt promised to sign
the Cullen-Harrison act
承诺签署库伦-哈里森法案
the minute he was elected,
全面开放禁酒
effectively ending prohibition.
- 你好 Figgis小姐
- 你好 Coughlin先生
- Hello, miss figgis.
- Mr. coughlin.
- 我能坐下吗
- 可以
- May I?
- Yes.
- 就坐一会 好吗
- 当然 请坐
- Just for a minute?
- Yeah. Please sit.
你看上去很不错
You're looking very well.
我看 你今天没穿白色衣服啊
I see, uh, you're not wearing white.
这件和白色差不多
It's almost white.
您需要点餐吗
Would you like a menu?
谢谢 先给我一杯咖啡好吗
Thank you very much. Could I have a cup
of coffee, please?
好的
Sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
为什么我父亲那么恨你
Why does my father hate you so much?
我是个罪犯 他是警长
I'm a crook. He's the chief of police.
他当然会讨厌我了
That's how it goes, I guess.
不是的 他曾经很喜欢你
No. He liked you.
他说你是依伯市长
He said you were the mayor of ybor.
- 他真的这么说过吗
- 嗯
- Is that what he said?
- Mmm.
你对他做了什么
What did you do?
对他吗
To him?
我们有照片
We had photographs.
你给他看了
And you showed them to him.
我给他看了两张
I showed him two.
一共有多少张照片
How many did you have?
全部都有
All of them.
我们都要下地狱了
We're all going to hell.
我觉得 你不会下地狱的
I don't think you're going to hell.
从这段将灵魂投身于上帝的经历中
You know what I learned as I've been
你知道我学到了什么吗
thrusting my soul out to god?
什么
What?
这就是天堂
This is heaven.
就在这里
Right here.
我们身在其中
We're in it now.
那为什么这一切都感觉像地狱呢
Then how come it looks like hell?
因为我们搞砸了一切
Because we fucked it all up.
在我的审判结束后
After my trials,
我睡在自己童年的床上
I slept in the bed of my childhood.
那种脚踏实地的感觉又回来了
I felt certain again.
我很怀念那种感觉
I missed that.
我不知道到底有没有上帝
I don't know if there is a god.
但我希望有
But I hope there is.
而且我希望他是个善良的人
And I hope he's kind.
那该多好
Wouldn't that be swell?
是啊 那该多好
Yes, it would be.
你看起来并不绝望 你有什么秘诀吗
You seem not to despair. Do you have a secret?
哪有什么秘诀
No. No secrets.
大概是因为我有个好妻子
I have my wife.
这就够了
That's enough.
如果你失去她怎么办
But what if you lose her?
你接下来想做些什么
What are you gonna do now?
你说什么
What do you mean?
你成功地阻止了我 阻止了赌场的建立
You stopped me. Stopped the casino.
法律没有做到 人民没有做到
Law couldn't do it. The people couldn't do it.
三K党都无法做到的事
The klan couldn't do it.
你做到了
You did it.
我并没有把酒精完全驱逐
I didn't get rid of alcohol.
那个目标太大了
No. That was too big.
但是你确实驱逐了赌博
在你没出现之前 我的赌场已经是板上钉钉的生意
But you've stopped gambling and before you came
along, that was a lock.
我的确做到了 对吧
I did do that, didn't I?
是的 你做到了
Yes, you did.
你父亲呢 打算做什么
What's your father gonna do?
坐在他的椅子上吧 大概
Sit in his chair, I guess.
被愤怒盲目了双眼
Blind with rage
因为竟有其他的男人 像他自己对待妻子一样对待他的女儿
that men touched his daughter the way he used
to touch his wife.
甚至更可怕
And worse.
他在房间里踱步 一遍又一遍地低诉
He goes around the house whispering
one word over and over.
说什么
What word?
忏悔
Repent.
忏悔 忏悔
Repent, repent.
给他些时间 他会缓过来的
Give him some time. Maybe he'll come out of it.
波士顿的消息 所有三条运货车都正常到达
We heard from Boston. All three trucks made
it up there fine.
利润也没什么问题 一切正常
Same payoffs as last week, so it's no problem.
很好
Good. Good, good.
还有 Loretta Figgis昨天割喉自杀了
And Loretta figgis cut her own throat yesterday.
什么
What?
昨天她在家自杀的 据说就在她父亲的床上
Yeah, she did it at home in the chief's bed, they say.
我还挺佩服她的
Gotta give it to her.
她还挺有胆的 我可没法这样去死
She's got moxie. I couldn't do that.
有些事就是命中注定吧
I don't know, i guess some things are meant to be.
不过 如果她早三个月自杀
Hell, she could've done it three months earlier...
那可是帮了我们大忙了
And done us all a fucking favor.
太迟了 唉
Too late.
圣 母 玛 利 亚 之 死
不要责怪自己
You blame yourself?
她去了西部 就像很多往那面跑的姑娘一样
She went out west as so many other girls do.
她只是被当成猎物捕获了
And she was preyed upon.
当然 不是被你捕获的
Not by you.
但她是被像我一样的人捕获的
By men like me.
像我们一样 有酒 有女人
Men who get the booze, they get the girls...
有毒品
They get the drugs.
一只手洗白另一只手上的罪恶
One hand washes the other.
我们并不是别人的守护神
We are not our brother's keeper.
事实上 如果我们认为别人需要我们的守护
这对他人也是一种侮辱
In fact, it is an insult to our brother
to believe we are.
看看这些人
Look at these people.
看这个人 如果他是个酒鬼 喝酒喝死了
If this man, say, dies of drunkenness
这也是我们的错吗
is it our fault?
这张照片什么时候拍的
When did you take this picture?
一个月前
A month ago.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我自己拍的 一个月零三天前
I took this picture myself a month and three days ago.
怎么了
Why?
因为照片上的女人 1927年就已经死了
Because that woman died in 1927.
我一生从没遇到过像你这样的女人
There has never been anyone like you in my life.
总有一天 我成为一个配得上你的好人
And one day, I'm gonna be good enough for you.
你确定这是她吗
Are you sure it's her?
你说呢
You tell me.
你告诉Graciela了吗
You tell graciela?
当然告了 你信吗
Of course I told her.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
怎么 你难道会跟你的女人说这种话
What? You wouldn't tell your woman?
当然不会
No.
我啥都不跟我的女人说 但你比我娘多了
No, I don't tell them shit. But you're more
of a Nance than me.
你要是告诉她 你该怎么说
What'd you say?
嘿 宝贝 抱歉 我之前为之心碎的那个女人 我以为她死了
"Look, sorry, hon, that girl I was bent out
of shape over for years
结果她没死 而且她就在迈阿密呢
"she's not dead. She's in Miami.
没啥大不了的
"Don't make a big fucking thing out of it."
你什么时候走
When you going?
- 去哪儿
- 别装傻了
- Going where?
- What do you mean, where?
你发现你心爱的女人还活着 而且只在离你200英里远的地方
You found out this girl you used to be bugs for
is 200 miles away.
你准备什么时候走
When you going?
等到和Maso这件事了结 我再做决定
Probably go after this thing with maso.
好的
Good.
能让你撑到活着做完这个了结
Give you something to live for.
你什么意思
What does that mean?
他和自己的手下塞了半列火车
Him and his guys are taking over half a train
to get down here.
这可是段声势浩大的旅程
That's a big fucking entourage.
该死 不用为这事担心
Ah, bullshit. I ain't worried about it.
他为什么要杀了我们 没道理
There's no percentage in killing us.
我们光是私酒生意就为他送上一千一百五十万美元
We do 11 and a half million dollars a year from rum alone
就在这么个小城市
in this fucking cow town.
他为什么要杀了我们
What's he want to kill us for?
我们天天给他往 纳罕特的别墅里面送钱
All we do is send him bags of money up to his
mansion in fucking nahant.
有不祥之兆啊
I don't like the signs.
- 什么不祥之兆
- 我们没盖成赌场
- What fucking signs?
- We lost the casino.
毒品生意也没有进展
We never moved on narcotics
你又是爱尔兰人 这就已经够弱势了
and you're Irish in a world where there ain't much
of a shortage in guineas.
他几乎包下了整个酒店 每个房间里都有他的人
Okay? You're walking into a building where he
bought up every room.
我连件武器都藏不进去
I can't hide a weapon.Nothing.
你到时候跟瞎子一样就进去了 我们只能在外面干着急
You're going in blind and we'll be outside.
这些征兆还不够吗
Is that enough signs for you?
你得帮我个忙
I need you to do something for me.
我需要你在迈阿密待一段时间
I need you to go stay in Miami for
just a little while.
一段时间是多长
How long is a little while?
我也不知道 不会太长
I don't know. Not too long.
我不能知道你的住处 你把地址交给Dion
I'm not gonna have your address. I want you
to give it to Dion.
风头过了 他会给我你的地址
When the time comes, he'll tell me where you are
我再去找你
and I'll come get you.
这样你就能发现自己到底够不够残忍吗
So you can find out if you are as cruel
as you need to be?
我猜是的
I guess so.
Joseph
Joseph.
就算你赢了今天这场战斗
Even if you win today's battle,
在你的黑帮江湖中仍然存在各种暴力
there's so much violence in what you do.
过来
Come here.
Gino 你现在住哪儿
Gino, where you living now?
尼庞西特
Neponset.
安顿下来了吗
Oh. Settling down?
有两个孩子了 有个大家庭了
Two kids. Mugghiera, casa. Whole thing.
你呢
You got any?
我还没想过呢
None for me.
这种事 没有时机合不合适这么一说
There's never a right time.
这边来
This way.
你好吗 我的孩子
How are you, my son?
很好
Fine.
Fausto 看看Dion需要点什么
Fausto, see if Dion needs anything.
你怎么样
So, how've you been?
挺好的 你呢
Good. You?
还行 好日子总比坏日子多
More good days than bad.
那好
Good.
这就是那个搞砸赌场计划的女人吗
This is the filly who fucked up the whole
casino thing?
是的 就是她
Yeah, that's her.
那为什么你没有动手杀了她
Why didn't you clip her then?
那样的话 引起的回火太大
Too much blowback.
不是这个原因
That's not it.
Joseph 你不是一个杀手
You're not a killer, Joseph.
你只是一个裹在西装里的强盗
You are a bandit in a suit.
这就是为什么你没有杀死这个——
That's why you didn't kill that
疯婊子
puttana pazza.
你知道我给你的帮派赚了多少钱吗
You know how much money this place was doing
when I got here?
- 你知道现在这里是什么情况吗
- 那只是私酒赚的钱
- You know what it's doing now?
- But that's all rum.
你撒手不管这个女孩 还有毒品 又怎么说
You neglected the girls and the narcotics.
因为我知道私酒是利润最高的生意
I went after the rum 'cause it was the most profitable
自从我到这来 我们又新开了四家私酒酿厂
and I added four houses in my time here.
但是你本可以赚更多的钱的
Yeah, but you could have added more.
Maso 听着
Maso, look--
叫我Pescatore先生
Mr. pescatore!
现在依伯和坦帕都是我的地盘了
你有什么意见吗
I ran ybor. I ran tampa. Did you ever have a problem?
你的地盘还要更大
You did more than that.
整个海岸线都是你的了
You ran the whole coast.
你把Albert White打击到迈阿密某个角落里苟延残喘
You boxed out Albert. Put him in a little
piss corner of Miami.
我有看账本 知道是怎么回事
I've been through the books.
你在这里发展了一支不小的力量
You made us a force down here.
现在呢 既然你的帮派不招爱尔兰人了 我该去哪儿
But now what? "No Irish need apply?"
What can I be?
我让你去哪儿你就去哪儿
What I fucking tell you to be.
不然我打烂你的嘴 蠢货爱尔兰佬
Before you get a fucking pop in the mouth, Mick.
你可以做参谋
You can be  consigliere.
教Digger一些本领 带他认识认识朋友
You teach digger the ropes. Meet people.
教他钓鱼什么的
Teach him to fish.
不过你该“理发”了
But you need to take a haircut.
“理发”是什么意思
What kind of a haircut?
理下来的“发” 你要交给让Digger掌管
Digger gets your take.
听着 Pescatore先生
Look, Mr. pescatore,
我觉得这是个很好的主意
I think it's a fabulous idea.
Digger来这里接管一切
Digger comes down here, takes over.
然后我们掌控整个佛罗里达 和那些古巴人
We'll run Florida, we'll take over Cuba.
但是我的分成必须基本保持原状
But my take's gotta stay somewhere near where it is.
如果让我做帮派的小头目 我不可能有现在的权力了
And there's no power in being crew boss and
shaking down longshoremen.
你难道就没看出来 我们就是这个目的吗 聪明佬
You ever think maybe that's the point, smart guy?
你需要我 我帮你建立了这座帝国
You need me. I built this.
我们要你还有用
We could use you.
但是我觉得你应该对我多点感激
But I'm sensing a lack of gratitude.
我也这么觉得
So am I.
你为我工作
You work for me.
并不为跟你整天混在一起的古巴黑人工作
Not the spics or the niggers you hang out with.
如果我让你帮我清理马桶里的屎 你猜猜 你该怎么做
If I tell you to clean the shit out of my toilet,
guess what you do?
我可以杀死你的贱货女友
I can kill your cunt girlfriend
把你的房子烧成灰烬 如果我兴致来了的话
and burn your house to embers if I feel like it.
所以 你是想做小头目
So, do you want to be crew boss
还是想帮我冲厕所
or clean the shit out of my toilet?
当然 如果你两个都想做 也可以
I'm accepting applications for both.
那就小头目吧
I guess it's crew boss.
这才是好孩子
That's my boy.
今天晚上一起吃晚餐吧 这边有几家不错的餐馆
You want dinner tonight? We have a few nice spots
set aside.
Joseph 你知道我喜欢Albert White什么吗
You know, Joseph, what I like about Albert white?
什么
What?
我喜欢他对坦帕也是一样了解
It's that he knows tampa too.
没人需要你了 傻逼
Which means nobody needs you, dumb fuck.
我的运气啊 变了很多
My fortunes have changed a little bit.
我和Maso谈妥了
Me and maso, we patched things up.
当你把赌场的生意搞砸之后 他来找我帮他儿子
Turns out when you blew the casino deal, he looked
to me to help his son.
这才是一切的开始啊
And that was just the start.
看见没
You see,
你得信任你的合作伙伴啊
you need to trust the people you work with.
我们加入这个游戏 并不是为了
We don't get into this game to place second.
当二把手 任人宰割的
To back the wrong horse.
就是这样
That's it.
你觉得自己明天能吃顿好饭 看看日落
You thought you'd be eating tomorrow, looking
at the fucking sun?
再仔细想想
Well, think again.
好好看看周围的一切吧
因为你马上就要看不到了
Take your last look because you die now.
等等
Wait.
Albert 我有你想看的东西
Albert, I have something
you wanna see.
一件不看你会抱憾终身的东西
Something that if you don't see, you'd
regret your whole life.
让你永远不会原谅自己的东西
You'd never forgive yourself.
她已经死了
She's dead.
她看着像死了吗
She look dead to you?
她在哪儿
Where is she?
她就在这张他妈的照片上 Albert
She's in the fucking picture, Albert.
- 她到底在哪儿
- 我愿意告诉你
- Where is she?
I- 'd love to tell ya.
但是我更想活着走出这里
I'd love to walk outta here more.
这照片是旧的
That's an old one.
- 你用旧照片糊弄我
- 我刚开始也这么以为
- You just folded up an old one.
- That's what I thought, too.
你看 角落里这男人拿的报纸
But, look, that guy in the corner
with the newspaper.
日期是上个月的
That was last month.
你告诉我 不然我就把你送进地狱
You tell me, or I'll put you in the fucking ground.
我也爱她 Albert
I loved her, too, Albert.
像你爱你现在那个女人一样吗
Like you love that woman?
是的
Yeah.
她是黑鬼 还是西班牙脏货呢
She a nigger or a spic?
都是
She's both.
不 不要
No! No!
你的人都他妈的是从哪冒出来的
Where the fuck are they?
去问Albert啊 他不是很了解坦帕吗
Why don't you ask Albert? He knows tampa.
Maso 你知道所有的私酒
You know why all the molasses and rum
that comes into Florida
是怎么从坦帕运出去的吗
comes through tampa, maso?
隧道
The tunnels.
什么隧道
What tunnels?
这里的街道下面全是隧道
The ones running underneath this neighborhood.
他们就是这样运输私酒的
That's how they get the booze in.
我的手下已经出动了
That's where my men are right now.
你的人守满了整个前门
Your guys are all standing around guarding the front door.
但我的人并不会从前门进来
But that ain't where we're coming.
我们已经冲着你来了
We're coming for you, maso.
但是我们走的是地下的路
But we're coming from below.
走啊
Go, go!
走
Go!
房间里都没人了吗
You cleared the room?
是的 整层楼都安全了
Everything. The whole floor.
Seppe 你再去检查一下
Seppe, give it another look.
老大 有人看见Coughlin在楼下
Boss, they spotted coughlin downstairs.
他受伤了吗
He even get a scratch?
头上破了一个口子
A cut on the head.
你们别等着他死 或者败血而亡了吧
I don't suppose you can wait for him to die
of blood poisoning?
等他死的话 我觉得时间来不及了吧
Well, I don't think we got that kinda time.
能有你这么蠢的儿子
It's a hard thing for a man
我活的也是太艰难了
to have a son this stupid.
都安全了 老大
All clear, boss.
你们把大门守好了
I want you to cover the door and the stairs
要牢得像罗马军队百夫长一样
like Roman fucking centurions.
给我倒一杯吧 好吗
Pour me one, will ya?
你躲到哪去了
Where were you hiding?
躲什么
Hiding?
Seppe检查房间的时候
When seppe cleared the room.
我就在这里坐着
Sitting right here.
我问他 愿不愿意为一个明天还能活着的老板工作
I asked him if he wanted to work for someone
who'd be alive tomorrow.
就这么个条件吗
That's all it took?
谁让你要把你儿子这样的蠢货带到坦帕来管事
That, and you wanted to put a fucking dunce
like digger in charge.
我们在这里有多好的生意啊 你只来了一天 就全毁了
We had a good thing going here and you fucked it
all up in one day.
你知道就因为你这套意大利纯血统的狗屎
让多少人在今天送了命吗
You know how many people died here 'cause of your
simple wop bullshit?
也许有一天 你也会有自己的儿子
那你就会了解我这么做的原因了
Maybe someday you'll have a son and you'll understand.
我能了解什么呢
What will I understand?
我儿子呢
How is my son?
他已经死了
Your son is dead now.
他们会要了我们所有人的命
They would have killed every last one of us.
会把我们赶尽杀绝 你知道的
Hunted us down. You know that.
大概他们也没想老死吧
They didn't expect to see old age.
我也是 没打算活到老
Neither do I.
杀死Albert之前
I had this whole thing I was gonna say
我准备跟他长篇大论一番的
to Albert before i killed him.
没来得及说
Too late.
好了
All right.
今天我不想再看到任何人被杀了
I don't wanna see anyone else get killed today.
你们有人想死吗
Any of you guys wanna die?
没有 Coughlin先生
No, Mr. coughlin.
如果有人想回到波士顿继续过日子
Whoever wants to go back up to Boston
那就回去吧 我祝福你们
has my blessing. Go ahead.
如果有人想留在这里
But if any of you want to stay down here...
阳光充足女人又漂亮的坦帕
Where the sun is warm and the girls are pretty...
我也有活给你们做
We got jobs for ya.
但我不干了
But I'm finished.
想找老板的话 去找Dion
You want the boss? Go to him.
现在他掌管一切了
He runs things now.
有什么不明白的地方吗
Any confusion on that?
很好
Good.
Graciela的地址
Graciela.
好了 我们走 大家收拾收拾吧
All right, let's go. Clean up this fucking mess.
Dion掌管了坦帕的帮派 整整八年
Dion ran the crew for eight years.
他说得对
And he was right.
他最终没有活到老
He didn't see old age.
有什么话赶紧说
Say what you have to say.
说什么
So, what?
你遭遇了车祸 然后你就想 我得借机逃走 对吗
You had the wreck, you thought you'd just
make the best of it?
不是
No.
那该说什么
Then, what?
到底发生了什么事 Emma
What happened, Emma?
当警察开始追我们的时候
Well, once the coppers started chasing me...
我跟司机说
I said to the driver, the only way
逃脱的唯一方法 就是把车开下桥
to get away was to drive off the bridge.
但他不听我的
But he wouldn't listen.
所以呢
So?
所以我就开枪把他打死了
So I shot him.
我掉进水里 然后游到岸上
We went into the water. I swam out.
跑到最近的有人的房子里求助
Ran to the nearest house with a light on.
收留我的是个渔民
He was a fisherman.
他乐意把我留在身边
Oh, he was happy to take me in.
你就没想过要找我吗
You didn't wanna reach me?
如果我稍稍出头 我就会被杀死
If I put my head up, they would've killed me.
我又不欠你什么
I didn't owe you.
我为你悼念了这么多年
I mourned you for years.
你告诉我 我该怎么可怜你呢
Why don't you tell me how bad I'm supposed to feel for ya?
如果我有一个来自爱尔兰大城市的
Oh, maybe if I had a police chief father
警督父亲 我可能还能理解你
from a nice part of Ireland...
但我没有 所以我也没办法
But I just had to make do.
你有没有爱过我
Did you ever love me?
我们开心过 Joe
We had a laugh, Joe.
我们之间有些美好的瞬间
Sure, there were moments.
但你却要把我们之间的一切认为成我们从未有过的东西
But you had to make it something it wasn't.
是什么
Which was what?
谎言
A lie.
我们并不是上帝的宠儿
You know we're not god's children.
也不是真爱童话故事里的主角
We're not fairy tale people in a true love book.
我们匆忙地舞蹈  这样才能阻止脚下的野草疯长
We dance like motherfuckers so the
grass can't grow underfoot.
我自由了 Joseph
I'm free, Joseph.
如果想拜访我的话  你已经得到了我的公开邀请
If you wanna come by now,
you got an open invitation.
我们总有一些欢乐时光的
We always had a lotta laughs.
我不想要自由
I don't wanna be free.
哦 拜托
Oh, come on.
自由 是我们一直都向往的
That's all we ever wanted.
那是你向往的
It's what you wanted.
现在你已经得到了
And now you got it.
再见 Emma
Goodbye, Emma.
我和Graciela建成了收容所
We built graciela's casitas...
收留那些被遗弃的无家可归的妇女和儿童
For abandoned women and children who needed a place to stay.
我给儿子起了父亲的名字
We named our son after my father.
他是个贴心又善良的孩子  像她妈妈一样
But he was thoughtful, kind like his mother.
你要去哪
Where you going?
忏悔
Repent.
过来 宝贝 让爸爸抱抱
Come here, sweetie. Let me pick you up.
忏悔
Repent!
- Tomas
- 忏悔
- Tomas!
- Repent!
忏悔
Repent!
你没事吧
Are you all right?
哦 不
Oh, no.
哦 不 不要
Oh, no, no.
哦 上帝啊 上帝
Oh, god! Oh, god.
哦 不
Oh, no.
哦 上帝 不要啊
Oh, god, no.
每个周六 我都会带儿子去看电影
On Saturdays, I take my son to the shows.
看到一个德国小老头  在大洋那边制造各种麻烦
Some little German guy is making trouble overseas.
不过我不相信世界又要为此陷入战争
I don't believe they'll fight another war, though.
至少几率不大
No percentage in it.
儿子很喜欢这部电影
My son loved the show.
电影讲述的是一个正义的小镇警长 在恶霸镇上除暴安良
It was about an honest sheriff in a dirty town.
东 岭 骑 兵
儿子一个劲地跟我说  长大以后也要当警长 带警徽、
All he could talk about was getting his own badge
when he grew up.
编剧 Daniel Coughlin
那是我哥哥
That's my brother.
那是我哥哥的名字
That was my brother's name.
那是你大伯
That's your uncle.
下午 我们会一起去钓鲑鱼
In the afternoons, we fished for red fin and snook.
有一天 儿子问我 这么大的天空 天堂在哪里
One day, my son asked me, "where's heaven in the sky?"
我想起了Loretta告诉我的话
And I told him what Loretta told me.
我跟他说 这里就是天堂
"This is heaven. Right here."
我们就身处其中
"We're in it now."
谢 谢 观 赏
翻译：RioLiv & Ash十架 @ 微博
水平有限请多指教 压制请保留译者署名